Welcome, child.
I am Ollie him.
Be welcome in this dream.
I'll never get tired of that.
I'm so ready, guys.
I've been pumped since yesterday.
After doing the translation stuff... oh my god.
Not that I haven't... not that I've translated every...
anything yet.
I just found part of a key.
And that got me so excited.
I have to keep playing.
Also, I apologize my voice is a little more echo sounding than normal.
I no longer have my pillow fort set up around me.
I was too lazy to put it up right now.
I just wanted to get right into it.
Hopefully it's not too bad.
How are you doing this Friday?
I'm doing great.
Limonade.
How was the event yesterday?
I saw a bunch of people joined for that.
It was good.
Very nice.
I think it's so cool you guys are enjoying your time together on that Discord and on the Minecraft server.
Such a cool community.
I'm so proud of you guys.
I think you would have enjoyed it.
I think so too.
Unfortunately, I already had a date set in place.
I was watching Starcraft.
In fact, I was watching Starcraft all day today.
I just finished watching Starcraft and I'm gonna keep watching Starcraft when I'm done with this stream.
There's a huge tournament going on right now.
It's amazing.
So the plan is to play Noiter.
And hopefully get to the bottom of what the fuck is going on in this world.
So what I'm gonna do is slowly do that and it's gone.
I'm so happy my game isn't crashing when I switch scenes.
There we go.
We've got the sound.
Everything's working.
Okay.
Nice.
New game.
We're almost at 100 deaths.
A couple more and we're there.
That's a whole milestone.
I do not intend to reach that milestone today, mind you.
Also, I'm experimenting with something new today.
I'm gonna have chat up on the left.
But like a smaller version of it, just so I can notice if something is wrong.
Because there needs to be some kind of way for you guys to more easily contact me if technical shit goes wrong.
We're gonna have to see how that goes.
Yeah.
Obviously, I'm not gonna look at the chat.
But just so you guys know, I won't be reading your messages, unfortunately, if you're trying to say something specific.
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold up a second now.
Look at that.
You see that text?
We can translate it now.
Hopefully, actually.
Now I'm nervous.
Hold up.
So it's like, let's try that.
Let's try it, man.
Here's our Rosetta Stone.
And the game says that thing, which is... Let's see if I can find it.
It's an R.
I'm gonna write some text here.
Oops, that's a straight line.
R.
And then there's this weird line, which is a V.
Wait, what?
And then a four, which is... The four is... Where is it?
It's the B?
Wait, what?
Then we have O, which I believe is... I actually don't remember.
The O is E.
R, V, B, E.
Set?
I don't think I found that one.
Wait a minute.
Oh, you know, it could also be capitalized, I guess.
Could be capitalized.
So the first one would be... If that is capitalized...
No, it's just still is big R.
R, V, B, E.
I don't think I found a set.
Oh, wait, wait.
It's more like a seven, I guess.
Have I found that?
I don't think so.
Could be D.
Okay, you know what?
That one is a bit weird.
So it has like this symbol, which is an O.
The fuck?
R, V, B, E, O?
I really hope I can actually translate this stuff and it's not like gibberish.
Well, we're gonna have to see.
Let's just move on for now.
I'm gonna check out some more translations when I find them.
And I'm gonna go up and grab the tablet from atop the... what's it called?
Mountain, as well.
Because I haven't translated that one yet, or at least gotten the ciphers from it, or the keys.
Also, guys, you're never gonna guess this.
Hey, holy shit, that's so hype.
And that's whiskey.
Let's get drunk.
Wasted.
Wait, drinking more will make you poisoned.
You drank way too much.
Oh shit.
Oh, I've never had this effect.
That's cool.
Happy Friday, everyone.
It's a good start.
You know, some people are higher functioning when they're drunk.
I'm not one of them.
Trust me.
I'm very much the opposite of that.
Let's see if we can't deal with these guys while being drunk.
They shoot green shit.
I shoot green shit.
Somehow I got them.
Also, I have polymorphine here.
This is bad.
That's re- What if I put that inside of a toxic sludge?
It goes to the bottom.
What if I put some whiskey in there, too?
Because this is what I also want to do today.
I want to do more mixing of liquids.
Alchemy.
I need to discover the secrets of the ancient alchemists of this world.
There are so many interesting mysteries in Noita.
And it's always intriguing.
I would say the only thing that I would wish there was more of in Noita is some more straight up lore.
But I could be wrong about that.
Maybe there is a bunch of lore hidden in the scribe, in all the symbols I see around the world.
And I just haven't translated it yet.
I am having an open mind regarding that.
But so far, I just love lore so much, you know?
Give me something, anything to latch onto.
Okay?
God, man.
There's already something so comforting about being in Noita.
Walking around, killing enemies.
It's like being home.
I'm gushing too much about this game.
Just a tad.
Did you see how many skips I did?
It's like skipping a rock on a lake.
Except it's not a lake and it's not a rock.
So it's actually not like that at all.
Look at this!
Long distance cast!
Vertical barrier.
Yo!
That one is huge.
Actually, I need to find water.
Hold on.
There's oil here.
And there's... Oh, hold on.
We can try some combinations here.
Mix it.
That's gotta make something.
No?
Okay.
There's like four different liquids in there.
Nothing is happening.
Okay.
I could probably set that on fire.
Do it.
That's gonna open a nice little path for me.
In fact, I'm gonna go down now.
Dude, long distance cast is big.
If we can find a teleport, we're golden.
All right, we got the money for long distance.
I'm grabbing it immediately.
Actually, not quite yet.
Whoa!
Did you see that dodge just now?
I think that was impressive.
A bunch of whiskey up there.
And here.
This is the most boost up hemisphere I've ever had.
So I'm in a bad spot up here.
I should probably not be up there.
Thank you.
Also, I'm drunk.
My aim is shit.
It's shite mate.
You see, high functioning alcoholic.
It works.
I'm at 100 HP.
Why do I have to say that right there?
It always backfires when I say it out loud.
I should keep those thoughts to myself.
All right.
Never mind.
I take it all back.
Also, I need to grab that water immediately.
Let's put some polymorphine in here.
In fact, let's try with blood.
What if we put this in blood?
And then put some of this in.
Mix it, mix it, mix it, mix it.
Is that doing anything?
Let's try and put some water in too.
Mix, mix, mix, mix.
The whiskey is not really mixing with the rest.
Is that making anything new?
I don't think so.
A bit of a bummer.
I'll be careful now.
There we go.
Now we get some water.
The most important liquid of them all.
All right.
I think that wooden thing has burned down by now.
Wherever that was.
Also, is this the tablet?
It is.
Yikes.
Put it here.
I want to go up here now.
I think this wand that I have in my hand right now is my favorite look.
Like, it's just so simple.
It's nice and blue.
It's just nice looking.
It's a great wand.
Visually.
Okay, so we have pheromone now.
No, a slime potion.
And we should try and mix that with some things as well.
I should put that in my little vat of mixed liquids that I have downstairs.
But hold on, what's this?
That's a very weird place here.
Look at that.
Also, I should be careful with that chest.
Thank you.
I cannot break that with the bouncing burst, unfortunately.
We're gonna have to bomb it to be safe.
Whoa.
Damn.
Seven spells per cast?
Hello.
All right, that's more like a close range shotgun, I guess.
Let's use it on these fools.
Whoa.
Oh, the sparkly bounce.
Ah!
Damn him has got the better of me.
All right, now we buy that.
Should I buy something else?
Homebringer teleport.
I think I want this one.
I think it could be really nice if you use it in the right way.
Remember how much damage it did to me when I stood in it?
If we can use that to separate us and some enemy and he keeps following us, could do a lot of damage.
Or put it on a trigger and have it appear wherever we shoot.
The thing about that...
I see you up there.
Oh, but you are caught in there, aren't you?
All right, I guess I'm not going there.
Let's go west.
Did I even find a heart yet?
I don't think I did.
Okay, we've got people downstairs.
Ah, I was here before.
Let me just blow it up.
I could have used this, damn it.
Give me the money.
Oh, wait a minute.
We've got tablets.
Shit.
Oh,
he's a friend.
Shit.
Is this friend burning me?
Friend, please stop.
I don't want to be a friend.
There we go.
That works beautifully.
Give me that.
I need that tablet though, but there's lava.
I thought that was way worse.
It was actually just okay.
Collapse the mines.
Uh oh.
Wow, the bleed.
Where are you?
There he is.
All right, going pretty well.
Oh,
my portal here.
So the big thing we need is something to dig with in the next stage.
Also, can I?
That does not really dig, does it?
I gotta get that from above, it seems, if I can.
I have one bomb left.
If I go like this, maybe it's possible.
Nice.
That's what I was looking for.
Yes.
Now we're cooking with diesel.
That's too much fire for me.
Uh oh.
That was bad.
That's bad.
Shit.
Okay, it's getting a little too dangerous here.
Water myself.
All right, wait.
I'm at 1 HP.
Oh, shit.
The portal is right down there.
Jump.
Go.
I didn't even realize I was at 1 HP.
Wow.
Come on.
Another long distance cast here?
What is this?
Come on, man.
Enemy radar.
Personal plasma beam.
You constantly fire a devastating plasma beam, but you fire spells much slower.
I like the first part, but the second part not so much.
I don't even have enough money for a re-roll.
I don't like these.
I will save my money.
And perks.
However, let me see what I can make before I go nuts here.
So this is not a... this is actually big.
This is not a shovel wand.
So I can potentially make something cool here.
So it shoots seven spells per cast.
Let me try something.
If I do this, it's obviously gonna shoot them both at once.
Yeah, but if I now do one, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
It's also gonna shoot two, but what if I put this here?
Wait.
No, it also shoots them.
It doesn't matter.
Okay.
That's what I imagined.
That's good to know.
So that doesn't matter.
But if I buy this now, and I put it here, and then I go... Wait, let me think.
I'm trying to think if I can put all of these bubble sparks inside of one trigger, because it's spells per cast seven.
I don't think I can, but let's try.
So it's gonna cast seven spells at once, right?
So one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
It's gonna cast all of these at once.
So that means it's gonna cast one spark bolt with that one on impact, and then all of these at the same time afterwards, but not contained inside of this.
Yep.
Exactly.
Okay.
That makes sense.
But with this,
30, and that.
Watch this now.
We're gonna do this.
We're gonna do that.
So one, two, three, one.
Uh, wait.
No.
One, two, three.
One, two.
That's it.
We can even remove these.
There we go.
Look at that.
That's a decent amount of damage.
Unfortunately, the recharge on it is utter crap.
But it was a nice experiment here.
I could also just go for a simple that.
Shoots fast.
You know, it's not the worst.
That may even be better for right now.
And then we can have a simple seven of these, or how many I'm able to.
Just as a shotgun thing again.
Close quarter.
Why not?
Now, unfortunately, I have to leave this place and collapse the mountain.
Yeah.
I also want to come back.
I want to grab this one.
I want to grab this one, this one, and this one.
Oh, actually, I already have one of those, so I guess not.
But they're kind of rare, so maybe it is worth it.
All right, let's go.
Not a bad start.
It was decent.
We got some decent spells on the horizon here.
Whoa, that's a bad start there.
Immediately, I get owned.
Where do you go?
Oh, he's down there.
I can't hit anything.
My aim is completely off today.
Got him.
Wait, that's burning way too much.
This does not dig, unfortunately.
It does dig, but only after they pop and it's always very hard to aim.
I do have one bomb left.
Shit.
I want...
Oh, wow.
That is insane, guys.
That's really good.
That's some solid shit right there.
The poop is solidified.
Let's watch this toxic.
I always want to watch the toxic.
What a shot.
What was that?
Oh, up here.
Oh, who's doing that?
Are you the one doing that, sir?
That's going to be teleporter here.
Ah.
Gunpowder arc and giant firebolt.
This is a lot of damage.
This is solid.
Let me try it.
Oh, yeah.
This is going to be my oh shit button if I need to kill something immediately.
I feel like maybe I should start... if I find unlimited spells or something, I feel like I should start making wands that utilize stuff like this more.
You know, like big hitters.
So far, I've been utilizing mostly simple spells.
And then I've been modifying them to shoot really fast and do a lot of damage, which is cool.
You know, it's a machine gun, but it would be fun to try other things too.
But now that I found the extra damage spell, I almost got to do that again, right?
It's so good.
So let's remember what my things are.
Yeah.
So here I can definitely use this.
That's a bomb.
Dang traps.
Wait, there's something in here.
Oh, it's a guy.
Let me try my new digger.
Oh, that's solid.
And a chest.
With a wand.
Always casts speed up.
Yo, that's dope.
And the wand slaps.
Five spells per cast, though.
Not super amazing, but I'll take it.
Firebomb.
Yo.
Oh, it's kind of shit as it is right now, but
the speed up really makes these fire bolts much better.
I can also dig with that sort of.
Give me the gold.
Where'd you go?
Dude, I'm going to go into fungal caverns.
We got to translate some stuff in there and kill some people.
We got to find out what's going on out there among the people.
Dude, this thing is literally shooting wherever I aim.
It is way better.
Oh, what?
I thought you were dead.
That just confused the fuck out of me.
I thought I killed him.
He was camouflaged by the fire.
No, thanks.
That is not intriguing.
Got another wand.
I can get it.
So this this is an amazing digger wand right now.
I love the effect of that explosion.
Magic bolts.
No.
No, thanks.
I do wonder if this will dig through the brickwork.
Wow, really?
Did you see that?
His shell bounced off the side of the coal pit there and hit me in the face.
He was so lucky.
Okay, be careful of that chest, damn it.
Uh, wait, I need to.
There we go.
Ooh, I have nightmares about chests in water.
Lesson learned, though.
Eldritch portal.
Huh.
No, I will not take it.
Or will I?
Wait a minute.
Yeah, no, no, this appears where you shoot it.
So it's bad.
You need to put that on a trigger, if anything.
I was thinking maybe I could use that for the fungal caverns.
It's a bad idea, I think.
Just die, please.
You are not even dead.
Look at all that gold there.
I want it.
Look how many of these I have.
I don't need to be stingy.
Oh, yeah, 500.
In fact, I'm going to go... Let me see, can I make a hole in this?
Oops.
I cannot.
All right.
I am going to go up, though, because I want to buy those spells before I forget.
Nice, made it.
Okay, do this.
There we are.
Make it nice and clean.
Just be careful not to sting, because that's a piece of concrete there.
That's better.
Reroll.
Oh, I like this one.
Yes.
That's amazing.
Give me that one.
This one.
And that one.
Maybe even this one.
All of them, actually.
And that one, too.
I buy the whole shop.
Did I heal in here?
I think I did.
I was at 1 HP, right?
Yeah.
Very good.
This is a solid start.
Now I just need to not die.
There's a bug on my leg.
Oh, it's just a fly.
That's what happens when you have the window open.
What's in here?
Oh, wait a minute.
I love this explosion.
I want to rapid fire this.
Yo!
Oh, nothing exciting, though.
Maybe that one.
I still do not quite remember what it does, but I think it's cool.
Wait, there's this gold line there?
How are you alive?
Okay, there we go.
I see you over there, sir.
You like that?
Oh, that did so much damage.
This one is going to come in real handy in the fungal caverns.
Oh, wait, my mouse is all fucked.
I had my mouse accidentally upside down, so when I went down, it went up.
That was weird.
I have no idea how I managed to bring the mouse upside down like that.
I'm honestly impressed.
Must have given it a pit maneuver.
Wait,
that's the top.
Nice.
Okay, guys.
Not bad.
Where is the... Oh, here we go.
Oh, no!
Immediately.
As soon as I encounter this fucking place, all hell breaks loose.
It's actually wild.
How crazy that place is.
And there's an enemy after me, and I can't see shit.
Oh, my God.
Fucking get this debuff off of me.
Actually, the worst place in existence.
Can't even get my foot in the door before everything goes to shit.
I'm not done, though.
It's personal now.
I need to fuck this guy up.
Oh, man.
Even he can't ruin my Friday mood, I tell you that.
Mark my words.
He thinks he can, but he's wrong.
Give me more water here.
Also, what is this one again?
It's slime, right?
I bounced off his ball.
Come on.
What the... are you?
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, shit!
It's going real bad.
There's some ones here, though.
You know, I should just use this.
Don't even play with me.
What do we got?
Huh.
Yeah, I don't know.
No.
There's another one there.
Any enemies?
Let's clear the area first.
Well, there was a guy up here who made me blind.
Oh, chaotic polymorphine.
This place is nuts.
I'm very low HP.
Oh, man.
Trying to grab that is going to be hell.
I'm going to clear up the area a little bit here.
I just want a couple wants for the road.
Wait, did that just evaporate the polymorphine?
I think it did.
That's pretty dope.
Spells per cast ten.
Damn.
But four seconds recharge?
Fucking yikes.
That's no fun.
What's down there?
Oh, wait, I'm electricity immune.
I can't be afraid of anything.
That's a terrible one.
That's worm pheromone and unstable teleportation.
I may actually take that instead of the slime.
The slime is kind of like one slime, right?
Not me.
Next.
I should really go through the portal.
I'm playing Risky.
Damn it.
This thing has so much weight to it.
There we go.
Just play that safe.
Give me that gold.
Yeah, got it.
There's chaotic shit up there.
What's below me?
Honey.
What's that?
Kiva Skibi.
Oh, I am terrified of this place.
Get me in there.
Get me in.
All right.
That's not a bad wand.
Honestly, .07 cast delay and average mana max and charge speeds.
These namona slots.
I gotta say though, this wand right here is probably the one, but it has five spells per cast.
I really dislike that.
See, that's what I love.
Killing those guys with explosions.
That's how you do it, because all of their offspring just immediately get killed in the process.
Or not.
Maybe you need a direct hit for that to work like that.
Oh, nice.
That was lovely.
Oh, that guy can fuck right off.
Also, there was a pouch up there.
Really want to grab it for my alchemy experiments.
But it's too risky.
I'm going to go up instead.
Check out this wand.
Maybe.
Did I already checked?
I checked that one already.
Uh-oh, there's another one of those guys.
I think it's time to fuck off.
We've checked out as much as we have the balls to do.
Unfortunately, no more balls.
I have ran out.
I'm not afraid to admit that.
Uh-oh.
Don't.
We got a portal.
I can explore more of the caverns here.
Just not the fungal ones.
What happened there?
Moss?
Toxic rock.
Oh.
I do wonder if... So with alchemy, if you can put in other things other than liquids and powders, you know?
Like, what if you put in like a whole mushroom or something?
Give me that gold.
Oh!
What?
Why did I get set on fire there?
Was it the explosion?
It's time to leave.
I have enough gold.
Yep.
Solid.
Okay, what do we have?
Oh, a teleport.
That's nice.
And what is this one again?
It's the burning trail, right?
Burning trail.
Oh.
Facing.
I... Hmm.
This one is good, I think.
Just nice to have in general.
I'm taking it.
I'm not sure I ever picked this up, but now I do.
Let's see how fast they fly.
Let's try that one.
Oh, that one is way better.
And this one...
Oh!
That's wild.
Look at that.
Pretty much instant.
But now we're gonna do some experimenting here with damage plus.
What does my best want?
It's probably this one.
How much, man?
100 recharge.
That's not bad.
Five spells per cast, though.
That's the big oof.
But you know what we could do?
If this is one spell, right?
Inside of that, we deposited some...
Let me think.
We do this again.
There.
We need some actual spells here.
Maybe I'll take that one.
Also, this costs 25 mana.
Recharge time is one second.
That's really bad.
Can we reduce that?
This one does... No, that's cast delay.
Recharged.
I don't think I can do that.
Okay, it's not that great, then.
Like, this may even be the best.
It looks so boring, but it's solid damage.
But I could definitely do something here.
It's just this recharge time really kills me, man.
It really does.
A second is horrible.
Let's do something like this.
There.
Then we're gonna need this to be in front of everything.
Because that's gonna modify this one.
Is that actually modifying the rest as well?
Wait.
Nah, the recharge time sucks.
Dick, I can't deal with it.
It's too bad.
Is there a way I can get out of this holy mountain without collapsing it?
I could maybe with the earthquake shot.
But a certain someone is not gonna be happy about it.
That is the issue.
Nothing else digs, right?
Long... Wait, long distance!
Bro, of course.
I'm an idiot.
We're gonna long distance teleport out of here.
I almost made a big blunder.
God damn.
That's the one.
Oh, but this is shuffle.
Hold on.
We need to put it on.
We actually needed to put it on up here.
Tell me we have enough mana.
Yeah, that looks fine.
That's great.
That's fantastic.
That's the teleport.
And then, for our main attraction, maybe we're just gonna go with a good old shuffle wand and put a damage in.
And, you know, on average, it's gonna increase damage.
It's not gonna be great, but it is what it is.
I'll throw on some of these.
Oh, actually, if I do this, then this is pretty much guaranteed to always apply to triplicate bolt.
Because let's say it shoots triplicate bolt first, and then this one after.
Oh, no, it doesn't work like that.
Or does it?
Oh, okay.
Sometimes it doesn't apply.
But this is, like, this is a solid situation we got there.
We can make it better.
That's not bad.
Maybe we add this as well.
Very nice.
What else should we add?
No, that's fine.
Yeah, that's cool.
I like it.
The shuffle really messes with me, but other than that, I think we're doing okay here.
These ones... not so sure about.
Although this one does have so much speed on it.
What can we do that would be really cool on this one?
Something is shotgunny.
Maybe, honestly, just the giant fire bolts.
The only issue is, it's gonna shoot five spells at a time, and I only want to shoot one of these at a time.
I guess I could just replace them all the time like that, but that's annoying.
Well, we do have speed up from the perk as well.
So, you know, I think it's fine to put them down here.
This is gonna be our big bomb wand.
Big bada boom.
I have another long distance cast that I could use with this.
It's not shuffled, so this should work.
Oh god, I'm scared.
Okay, I need to try this.
We got to try that.
But the only issue is that I kind of want to keep a wand free in case I need to pick one up.
But I actually like this one.
I don't like this one.
Yeah, we're gonna replace this one, because I think this one could be a sick wand later on.
If we get the right stuff for it, you know, I just imagine we can do something with it.
Yeah, I will even leave one of these up here, just because in case I find unlimited spells, and I can use this with another one later, and I end up replacing this one, bada boom.
Okay, I think we are ready.
170 HP.
Should I buy anything else?
You know what?
Get me another one of these.
Yeah, that's good.
And maybe I'll take that one as well.
I don't think I like the fire stuff.
Not when I'm...
Not fire immune.
The magic bolt.
13 damage.
Hold up.
That looks really cool, actually.
Oh, but it's wildly inaccurate.
Look at that.
Oh, it adds five degrees of spread.
Oh, but that's five degrees is a lot, man.
Look at that.
That's super inaccurate.
What the hell?
Whatever.
I like this.
The spread is still kind of a lot on it, but it is what it is.
Okay, let's move.
Go through here.
Boom.
Awesome.
Okay, this one is very inaccurate.
But the good news is we can always come back and change our wants.
I really hate the people shooting these balls in the air here.
They always seem to hit me.
I have such trouble evading them for some reason.
It's like a weak spot in my brain when it comes to that form of evasion.
Let me put this on three.
There we go.
Much better.
Should I be grabbing that gold?
I think so.
Yep.
That's invisiblium.
No!
His body fell on it.
Yo, what's what's with that guy's HP?
That was out of this world.
Wait, dude, my shield is doing work.
This is a crazy good spell to have.
It's basically like half a permanent shield and you gain it from a spell.
Not even a perk.
That's wild.
That's a lot.
Oh, dude, if I find one of these eyes in here, I'm going to try the teleportation.
I do have unstable though, so I have my doubts, but we're going to try.
Also, are you noticing how I should be using only one of these instead of both of these?
Because I end up doing less damage.
Because the extra damage effect is being applied much less often.
I need to go back and change that.
I just noticed.
Look at this.
It's very rare that the effect is being applied here, but I mean, no, no, no, let's keep going.
Let's find an actual wand that doesn't suck.
And then we put it on there.
We just need one non-shuffle wand that is like halfway decent.
And then we're golden.
Oh, that went straight through my shield.
I think it's because he shoots three shells.
One of them gets absorbed by my shield.
The other two go through.
So I've changed my stance on vampirism now.
I think I may...
It's not number one, but it's so here's the thing about vampirism.
Early game, it's actually king.
Vampirism for me is what makes a run a potential amazing run.
It sets things up.
You know what I mean?
So, but late game, it's not that good anymore.
Like very late game, it's kind of useless, but it is what allows you to get to late game.
At least in my case, it's super useful.
Okay, so here can I... I have the teleport wand.
I have to remember, but I'm not gonna...
I'm gonna be a little safe here.
Ah, oh, that's right.
It's not a small teleport.
It's a big one.
We're in the big leagues now.
Okay, there's like two guys in there.
Oh,
I see you.
Are you dead?
You are.
So I think my plan is to teleport through, use my big bada boom.
Easy.
Plasma beam cross.
Ah, I shuffled.
This would have been a sick wand otherwise.
But I guess there is like a perk that allows you to do a change, a wand from shuffle to non-shuffle, right?
Don't think it's worth it, though.
I mean, it would really have to be a crazy wand.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Shit.
I'm playing really bad right now.
Water myself.
There we go.
Water meself.
I don't know why that just came out in my moment of frustration there.
There we go.
A small teleport.
I'll take it.
We can switch that up ASAP.
Let's just continue on a little bit more.
Oh, yeah.
Lovely.
How many do I have left?
Quite a lot.
The ammo is great.
Will you stop shooting that?
Okay.
143 HP.
Not the worst.
700 goldies in the pockets.
Oh, hello.
I'm not gonna risk him doing anything.
You are gone.
All this toxic sludge.
Oh, that was scary.
Someone died here.
Ambrosia.
Don't break it, please.
So, I'm immune to electricity, but I'm not immune to explosions.
So, those ukos are still dangerous AF.
Let's just wait it out.
Okay.
So, I'm getting rid of my whiskey.
I'm getting this.
Solid.
Polymorphine.
Whoops.
Oh, I really need that small teleport.
The long distance teleport is, or the long teleport, is scary stuff.
And you have no clear idea how long there is of a distance on the other side.
It is dangerous.
Oh, man.
Guys, is there anything better than Friday and video games?
I don't think there is.
Maybe I'm a simple man.
I am a simple man.
Hello.
Sup, fool?
Oh, man.
My shield is doing wonders.
It's bouncing off all kinds of potential damage that I would have taken otherwise.
Can you just die, please?
Okay.
What is all this?
Oh, it's snow.
Why is there so much of it here?
I guess it's because we're in the snow level.
Why do I ask stupid questions?
I love booping.
Whoop.
Show me the money.
Give me the water.
And let's go do some slaughter.
And raise a daughter.
You.
How did I miss that one?
There we go.
Get your ass out of here.
Okay.
I don't risk taking that money.
Nope.
I will check this out.
All kinds of goodies for daddy.
I may take it.
But I'm going to go back first and deposit some wands and switch up some spells.
So this one is down to the bottom right somewhere.
Let's remember that.
Oh.
Oh, God.
A little bit too scary for me.
There's a propane tank right there.
How did that not blow before?
Lucky me.
I could have been really bad.
I'm just happy I have eyes in my sockets.
Something I've noticed.
The soundtrack in Neutze.
In the first level, there's almost none of it.
And then in the second, there's a bit more.
And in this one, it's almost constant.
And then as soon as you get to the jungle, then there's just blasting music.
It's like it goes up in intensity all the time.
The deeper you go.
Kind of a neat detail.
Will you stop?
Oh, I have no more big bombs.
Crap.
Boink.
Oh, that was bad.
That was really bad.
Oh, come here.
Come here.
Gotcha.
1200 gold is respectable.
Is that?
That's worm blood.
Let's try and make some Ambrosia in there.
And some Invisiblium.
Mix it.
No, wait, this is unstable teleportation.
Never mind.
Chili water.
Oh.
Don't think I've ever seen that before.
I've seen water and I've seen ice.
I don't think I've seen the in between there.
Okay, let's go back to base.
I mean, we're still gonna explore, but we're doing it on a path back to base.
Oh, these explode.
What?
Wow.
We need something bigger for that.
The old triplicate.
It's not enough.
The fuck?
All kinds of shit falls from the sky.
That you throwing snot at me.
A strategy that I find much success in is to backtrack to already explored areas when I have enemies on me.
I just keep going back like this.
It's a solid strategy and it always seems to work.
Like if you actually do it and you stay disciplined.
Holy shit.
Wait a minute now.
Critical plus and ball lightning.
Imagine putting on that 70 mana drain though.
Oh and 0.83 castellae added on top.
Yikes.
I was gonna say, let's just throw a bunch of these on a trigger.
Would be dope.
I guess I could replace this one.
Am I really gonna... Maybe I will recharge this later on or will I?
Huh, let me think.
No, I'm not gonna use this.
The only one I would use is that one and I'm gonna take it to bring it back and put it on my wand.
Other than that, I'm not gonna use the ball lightning.
See, this is me being safe here.
I could just long distance through here but I don't know what's on the other side.
What's that?
Kiva skeevy.
Fishes.
Can I eat fishes?
I wonder.
Can I somehow bring them with...
Wait a minute.
Also, there's something in here.
Oh yeah, there's something in there.
Nope, there's not.
There's a chest up there.
I saw it.
Oh man, the wand is not bad.
It's just that it only has two slots.
That's really annoying.
Could be nice and have teleport on it though.
This is a nice teleport wand.
Well, it's 0.65 recharge, so it's not amazing.
Let's leave it here for now and grab the chest.
Yo!
Not bad.
Leave it.
Nice.
Okay, first things first, replace that.
Never want to see that one again.
This can go here.
The critical plus...
Ah, let's see here.
Do I have any methods now of reducing recharge time?
Don't think so.
Man, I really want to make something great out of this wand, because it has the always speed up on it.
But maybe I'm reading too much into that.
It's not really that cool.
Like, it's no better than a usual speed up I put on a wand, I guess.
I think I'm over-valuing that a little bit.
So hold up.
How often is this...
So it's mostly affected with the buff.
I mean, sometimes it's not, but mostly.
Wait a minute.
I can make this always be affected, can I?
If I do this, it's either gonna shoot... Wait, wait.
This is the trick.
I'm trying to see if I can find clever ways to circumvent a shuffle and use it to my advantage somehow.
If I had a double spell here, I could make sure that whenever this thing was fired, it would always have a buff on it.
No matter what, right?
Because if you have something in a double, I don't think the shuffle one will shoot something inside of the double itself.
It would only shoot the double because that's a spell.
You've basically made one, like, overarching spell with smaller sub spells inside of it, right?
And that is considered one spell in this case.
Um, yeah.
Let me see here.
I mean, changing the order here is not gonna do much, but it's better than nothing right now.
I just really wish I had found a better wand.
Let's get rid of these as well.
Let me see the damage on this.
I think it's better.
I could even do that.
Oh yeah, that's sick.
Oh, but I do run out of mana with that, but it takes a while.
Maybe this is better.
It's hard to say.
Hold on, let me put this on here again.
I feel like it's so slow.
It's just terrible, but I could do something like this.
You know?
And then at the end we could have a... do I have another one?
I don't think so.
So I guess a triple is fine here.
Like this is gonna... whoa!
So that is doing 65 damage.
What if I put this like that?
Oh!
Hold up!
The damage plus does not cascade into the triple scatter.
Interesting.
And this one doesn't matter where it is in here.
Yeah, I learned that last time.
It can be anywhere, which is kind of odd to me, but okay.
I mean, that is a lot of damage.
It's just the recharge time is killing me.
Yeah, it is what it is.
So if it ever shoots that one only, then it's really good.
Let me see how this does.
No, that's absolutely horrendous.
So if you ever want to do this, you gotta do it like that, I guess.
Just one of these.
But then you use this one like we had before.
Yeah, that's solid.
For now, at least.
Now on the other ones.
Also, this distribution switched around.
On the other ones.
Wait a minute.
0.02.
Odd shuffle as well.
That's a solid teleporter.
I think for the most part here, I'm happy.
Let's go collect some of those ones we left behind.
And find a proper one.
Really want to find a black hole or something and make Stuart mad and go back to the area above.
Find some ones there.
What is that one there?
Freezing liquid, okay.
Levitation.
There's a one there.
Let me in.
Which one was this?
Right.
Now, two slots is simply too little.
You can't really do anything with that.
I'm doing decent damage with this one right now.
Despite the fact that it's a shuffle one.
Polymorphine.
I've mostly been here, I think.
Not in there, but I don't think there's anything in there.
I think I've explored most of this place.
Oh, wait a minute.
What?
No way!
What is that?
Don't mind if I do.
That's crazy.
A giga death cross?
Oh, luminous drill.
Yo.
Let me put it here.
You know what I think happened here?
So this is a thing you need to fill up with a certain something.
It's already filled.
By pure chance.
And then there it is.
Hold on.
Can I figure that?
So blood is the thing you need to fill it with, obviously.
But what was the hint for blood then?
Maybe there was a little pool of blood already down here at the beginning.
But hold on.
Triangle.
Upside down triangle.
Maybe that means blood.
Hold on.
Maybe I'm just going to write this down for now, because maybe there's something to it.
Even though we know symbols usually mean one letter, but this could be blood.
And that's very not sure.
I'm not very sure about that.
So I'm actually going to put it in a cloud.
Because it's a dream.
It's not real.
It's in my thoughts.
Like a thought bubble.
Speaking of blood.
Holy shit.
Okay, I haven't been here.
That's good news.
What is that?
Is that worm?
Blood it is.
Wait, I have been here.
But I've not been to the left here.
Ah, we've got more wands.
That could be the one.
I really need a decent non-shuffle wand so I can go back and put all of these awesome things I just got on it.
I could go in here.
Yeah, do it.
Not afraid.
I'm not afraid.
Wait, I'm afraid.
I'm afraid.
Get out!
Oh, scary stuff.
I can't help but feel I'm doing this in a bad way.
Let me go up top.
Yeah, I haven't been up here.
Lovely.
Oh, I hear something.
Yeah, I heard you.
Come on.
Come on, Uco.
There we go.
That's berserkium.
See, I just got saved there.
I would have taken damage if not for my shield.
Oh, yeah.
Hold on.
Let me go grab my wand.
Where was it?
Somewhere down.
Wait a bit.
Okay, someone is wilding over there.
There's my wand.
See, that's what I'm talking about.
Oh, no.
The mana charge speed is low.
Shit.
It was almost the ideal wand.
Oh, but it is because we have had mana.
Also, hold on.
Do I have anything I can reduce?
I do.
Recharge time.
Oh, this adds castile.
Reduce recharge time.
This is actually a solid way of doing that.
Also, it always shoots piercing shots.
Interesting stuff.
I think I'm going to replace this one.
It feels bad to say,
but I'm going to...
No.
Ideally, I want to replace this one.
Ah, it's just annoying going back and forth like that.
Ah, so what I'm going to... Ah, this is... Okay, I'm going back.
This is why you need to tinker with wands everywhere, because you don't want to do this shit every time.
Good thing we have teleport, though.
Ouch.
Wait, there's a...
My wand!
I need that.
I'm coming back for that one instead, then.
That's even better.
Ah, I can't get through.
Unfortunates.
The wand was right there all this time.
Okay, so here's the plan.
I'm going to put this here for now.
Then I go down and grab the wand.
Leave this one here.
Nice.
So good.
And now we're rocking and rolling, baby.
So let's see now.
Oh, this is going to be wild.
And this even has a good mana charge speed as well.
Oh, damn.
Let's think.
Critical plus.
Let's do a nice spark bolt into a nice quadruple.
And we leave this inside of there.
Maybe this one as well.
Yeah, just sparkle at the front with some nice damage and that one.
And maybe we can double dip on the add mana.
Hold on.
Put this here for now.
First of all, let's just see how this looks and feels.
I think I want to throw in...
...triplicates in here.
One, two, three, and then...
Hold on.
Okay, so we're limited by recharge time now.
So what if we... because this also does damage.
Yo.
Hold on.
This is way better.
Work on a... wait, no, no, no.
That one.
Okay.
Yes, yes.
Add mana.
We need just a tiny less amount of recharge.
How can we achieve it?
Yes.
Maybe by... so one, two, three...
I mean, that's solid already.
I hate that this thing breaks and it's useless after a while.
Let me think.
Giant explosion on drunk enemies.
Wow.
Ooh.
Oh, this adds spread.
Okay, I'm lacking a bit of slots here.
Maybe I just remove this.
Hold on.
I need to test on the statue to see what the damage is like.
Don't tell me I can't see the damage with the luminous drill.
Please tell me that's not the case.
This fucking statue.
Oh, that's so annoying.
I can't tell my DPS.
God damn it.
Okay, I'm just gonna assume it works this way where...
So these do 10 damage.
I'm effectively adding 10 damage to each of them.
Right.
That's what I'm doing.
Castelay is essentially zero.
Well, it is zero.
Recharge time is the only thing.
So we're minus 0.37 recharge, so we still have a bunch of recharge left.
I guess we are working with kind of a bad wand.
I forgot what recharge time the other one that I found had.
We're gonna go check it out.
But for now, this is a good start, I think.
We do that.
We can even add some mana.
And there it is.
That's a solid DPS right now.
Solid amounts of DPS.
This is a projectile modifier.
Let me see the board.
All right.
It always adds one of these.
Can we afford a bit more damage?
So one, two, three.
There.
Pompompompompomp.
Oh, we actually run out of mana with that.
How about now?
This is actually bad.
This is faster.
Yep, that's good.
And we add this at the end.
Have some protection.
The only question is, I don't know if this is gonna be better if I add this in here or not.
I don't think it is for now.
I'll put this up here.
Now all of these...
I may just put this wand on the floor.
Because... okay, so here's the thing.
It has piercing.
So this can come in handy later.
I want to keep this one as well.
Let's put this on the floor.
Wait a minute, why does this one have a two next to it?
You see it up there?
Is it because of that one?
Oh, it is!
Okay, never mind.
It was because of that one.
All right, let's put it here.
It even has a name.
Look at it.
Valtika.
All right.
So far, so good.
We have a pretty sick wand already.
I
think I've checked both of these.
Yeah.
Hold on, let me just double check.
Ah, it's shuffle!
And it's shuffle.
Although, electric charge could be cool.
Because I'm immune to electric.
Let's just deposit that in our bank.
Don't mind if I do.
Duh duh duh duh duh duh duh duh.
Uh, deposit it.
Let's leave this.
No, leave...
Oh, I don't know.
That one here.
And then put this up here.
And... Oh, wait a minute.
Eight, eight, eight.
Dude, these do eight damage for the cost of five mana?
Hold up.
That could be really sick.
We don't even need an ad mana.
Well, not real.
No, I like it better the way I had it before.
Oh yeah, that's better.
All right, I will keep some of these though.
Could I put this in here now?
Let's experiment with it.
Let's do that one.
Yep.
And it has electricity now.
So watch this.
Uh, let's find some water.
Oh, wait, what?
I thought it would electrify the water.
Hmm, disappointed.
I was hoping I could electrify people in liquids.
Maybe I can.
Maybe it's so instantaneous you don't notice it.
Oh yeah.
This is the one I think.
It has 0.5 recharge.
Oh, but it has three slots, six slots.
One, two, three, four, five.
Oh, no, it's not good enough.
Not for what I want to do.
Or maybe it is.
I mean, you know, it would need to be experimented with.
I just don't want to go back to base again.
I'm tired of going back to the mountain.
I don't want to see mountains again, Gandalf.
Mountains no more.
What the fuck?
Did I just kill all these guys with the ice falling?
Amazing.
That's honestly incredible.
Boop.
There's stuff up here.
Ouch.
Well, that's going to be annoying.
What's this?
Poison.
Nope.
I will skip that.
Oh, shit, I got stunned.
Getting hit by those things stuns you briefly.
Wait, he blocked?
I'm actually kind of low here.
I think it's time we leave.
Yeah, blade safe.
Go to familiar parts and leave.
I hear the thing.
I'm not going to teleport through, though.
That's a bit risky.
If there's an enemy down there and I can't see him.
Let's just do this.
Go.
Yeah.
Nice.
Okay, a double.
Trick plot money.
Low key mutation, high mana, low capacity.
Wait.
No, no, no, no.
Nope.
We're rerolling that.
To fart.
Projectile duplication.
I'm more vulnerable to projectile damage.
I don't like that part.
That scares me.
I don't like these, but I am.
I should try new things.
I'm going to try this one.
We're trying new perks.
Let's see how that works.
I'm not sensing a duplication happening.
Oh, yeah.
I think I saw three of these luminous drills there.
Sometimes.
Yeah.
Oh, sometimes there's four.
Okay.
I see.
Sometimes three.
Okay.
It's just a solid DPS increase, but I also take a bit more damage.
Hopefully I do more damage on average than I take.
Double spell.
And that one is random projectile spell.
You know, that could be interesting.
How about we try it?
Because if it's on a trigger...
Wait, I bought the wrong one.
Fuck.
Also, what?
Hold on.
Oh, these add cast alike.
Crap.
This is 20 mana.
How about I throw this in here?
Oh, okay.
Oh, did I just anger someone?
Oh, no.
Oh, the chances.
Maybe I'm good enough to kill him.
Hey, fuck it.
I'm not.
I'm not good enough.
Shit.
Tablet.
Tablet time.
Let's see if I can do it this time.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, fuck.
It's over.
God, fuck.
What are the chances of this happening?
This is wild.
Oh, God, damn it.
Oh, no, I have to escape him.
It's a disaster.
We're at 40 HP, man.
This is just...
Never use random again.
It's the worst idea.
Wait, what is happening here?
I feel like...
Okay, never mind.
How do we deal with you?
Can I really not penetrate your shit?
Oh, briefly, I did.
Sir, that's the strategy.
Bounce off the wall with the luminous drills.
Haha.
Sick.
Unfortunately, we're low HP now.
Okay, back to business.
Uh, rip.
I think... Okay, I think the vertical barrier could have maybe killed him.
If I'd put it here, had him walk through it.
I don't think I ever tried that.
For now, though,
I'm not sure.
I feel like I've been finding shitty wands.
This run is just shitty stats all around.
You know what?
Let me do this.
Why not?
So the plan now is to heal, which means going...
going to the portal.
Pretty much immediately.
Oh, fuck me.
That was a friendo.
Do I don't have pheromone, do I?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, what?
What the fuck just happened?
I gotta see that again.
Huh?
Okay, he must have had some kind of spell on that wand that duplicated that initial crystal everywhere.
I can't explain it otherwise.
Like, look how it just goes everywhere.
Like, it's just bang, bang, bang, bang.
What a death.
The worst part is he got me in death.
Like, I killed him.
But his one shot fucked me up afterwards.
That's unreal.
Yikes.
That's 99.
We're not going to 100.
Uh, we are back.
I gotta open my window.
It's getting a little too hot in here.
Okay.
Much better.
All right, we have bombs that I cannot utilize.
I think if you're pro enough, you can maybe do it up here.
I'm not pro enough, because it activates after a very long delay.
You would have to be quite high up when shooting it.
And I don't have the skills for that.
Okay, we're starting off solid here, finding a wand.
Okay, I'm predicting there's a circle of resuscitation on that.
Or whatever the fuck it's called.
Imagine if I'm right.
It's a bit of a waste to use a bomb here, so I could do this.
That's gonna make its way in.
What's over here?
Blow it.
Also, we have blood.
Okay.
Gotcha.
This thing is slowly working its way through the wood.
He's actually helping me dig right now.
Thanks, man.
Okay, that works as well.
That really works.
Oh wait, I forgot about my new thing I wanted to try.
Again, Stuart, I wanted to try and kick my tablet instead of throwing it.
Fuck.
I thought about that last time and I completely blanked on it right now, but I just remembered.
Because I had the idea right now.
Circle of stillness into tablet.
That made me think of it.
Ah, shit.
Blood me up.
Blood me up, fam.
A wand.
With an air- Ooh, yo, wow, look at the stats on that.
Holy crap.
That is really nice.
It's gotta be my main damage now.
Yep.
Uh-oh.
Ha ha ha ha.
Hey, horta.
Ah, it's stuck.
Fuck.
Ah, shit, that's not water.
Gotta find water first.
Very
nice.
That is electricity.
Do it.
Fuck, that scared me.
What a shock.
Uh, Amos?
Look at that one.
Polymorphine.
I can get through here.
What?
That's unreal.
Oh, but hold on.
I have fire.
There we go.
Everything is okay.
We're back in business.
Okay.
Let's go check it out.
Oh, but wait, we need water to get in there.
Dang it.
Let's find some water.
It's water time.
Can't even get through there, because I don't have water.
So down here...
Should be a tablet.
Oh!
I didn't see you there.
There's a wand?
No.
Just bomb it.
Oh, I could have done this one.
What's done is done.
There we go.
That's it.
Oh, god.
Get rid of this blood.
No, actually get rid of this instead.
Maybe a bad idea to just throw it there, but...
That's okay.
If I make one bad idea now, I'm never gonna make more bad ideas this run.
You know, I exhaust all of my bad ideas very early on, so I don't make them later when it really matters.
Flawless logic.
Nice.
What is this?
Dude, that's another crazy good wand.
Yes!
It's just sad that it only has two slots, but it would be incredible.
Had a little bit more.
Even three would be so much more better.
Uh, here I can get through like that.
Hey, miss.
Oh, what a shot.
Robin Hood here.
Okay, it's tablet time.
I do like how it looks that the arrows get stuck in terrain and stuff.
That's a nice effect.
I really like that.
I should actually check out each of these portals, because sometimes there's a hard ride in there.
Okay, there's nothing.
Imagine if they're watched there just now.
I would have looked so smart.
Oh, what's up fools?
Someone fell into my little trap down here, didn't they?
Maybe it was a good thing I did after all.
Polymorphing this whole area.
For all I know, that was a tough enemy down there.
Wait, is this a wand I've checked?
It is.
Now, how am I gonna...
I need to use my tablet.
Here.
God damn.
Hey, miss.
Hey, miss!
Sweet!
Hey.
Nice.
That could have gone better, but I'm not unhappy about it.
Boing.
Hey, how did you survive?
Read a book.
Boink.
You know what?
I think that counted as an accident.
There's no way there was that many hammers there.
Did you see all that gold?
I think if you destroy environmental explosives, that counts as well.
Oh, man.
What a dodge.
Solid amount of gold I've got so far.
Like, watch this.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Ah, you know what?
I'm too lazy.
Water this.
Oh, man, look at all that.
Toxic.
Oh, my God.
I'm so slippery.
Get in.
Oh, don't get too... Actually, get out of here.
What the fuck am I doing?
There's no reason to be here.
Does not lead anywhere, obviously.
What is over here?
Collapsed mines.
Tablet.
Sweet.
Except he didn't die from it.
So, savory.
Can I get in there?
Also, I have circle of stillness.
It's going to take a while.
Unless... I have an idea.
It's going to be the craziest.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Down.
Gently.
Oh, perfect, perfect.
Oh, come on, come on.
Yes.
No!
Come on, make me look good.
Come on!
It was almost cool.
It was almost there.
Ah, it's going to be hell to get in there.
Oh, my God.
I'm having dumb.
Ah!
Wow.
Um...
Not the greatest.
But I like it more than this one.
I just don't have any digging now, but that's okay.
I'll survive.
Slimy egg.
What the fuck is that?
Runestone of fire!
Say what?
Oh!
Wow!
It sets things on fire!
That's fucking cool.
Very nice.
It's the first time I've seen that.
Oh, but enemies projectiles work the same way.
Yeah, that makes it a bit complicated, doesn't it?
Unless you're immune to fire, then that could be really cool.
Whoa.
Oh, man, that was beautiful!
Two super hard enemies taken out with one stone.
Uh, I will take this.
Sure.
Fungal soil.
Oh, my goodness.
Is it my time to leave?
Is it time to leave?
Maybe not quite yet.
No, that's the edge.
Let's leave.
Let's see what we got.
Is this for real?
Holy fire!
Everything is fire in the shop!
Wait, what?
Oh, right.
That one.
Um...
Hmm.
Reroll that one.
Oh, I hate these two.
Oh, that's not bad.
Let's do that.
This is what's going to kickstart the run.
You know, similar to Vampirism, this is what's going to allow me to make great things happen later.
All right, so we have some great ones, actually.
Um, I like Energy Sphere.
Like, that's a solid amount of damage right there.
You can't be mad about that one.
The rest I really don't care about.
This is all useless for me.
Although, that wand is not terrible.
0.12 cast delay.
But the recharge time is a little bit bad.
But it has lots of slots.
I still don't think I'm happy with it.
This one for sure.
0.1, 0.2...
Is that the same wand?
It is.
That one.
Um, I'll put that there and use that here.
And then these two wands can stay here.
Yeah.
This is my simplistic setup.
I have Fungal Soil.
Is that going to make fungus grow?
Is it growing?
I think it is.
Let's make a nice little garden in here.
We come back later and get high as fuck.
Hopefully, the cops won't see us growing this.
Oh, yeah.
Look at this.
All right, this can grow for a while and we'll be back.
Also, I'm not healing yet.
I want to find a couple hearts in here, ideally, before I heal.
Oh my god, can you please not fucking come on?
Oh,
wait, I have no digging.
Yeah, we got to find something to dig with.
Or blow that up.
There's a chest.
What the fuck is that?
Kami?
Hold on, is that an item?
Let me get rid of this one.
Huh?
Say what?
Can't be thrown to summon a cozy hut?
The fuck does that mean?
I mean, other than what it says.
Hold on.
Kind of want to get rid of this now.
Maybe we turn it off.
Boing.
I'm going to try it.
Get rid of that.
Oh no.
I could have healed in there.
But I couldn't get in.
Oh, I should have stood on it.
I was afraid I was going to die.
I didn't know what would happen.
All right.
Well, that's crazy.
I've never seen this item before.
And randomly, it's just here.
This game keeps surprising me.
Like, this is why this game is so awesome, man.
There's seemingly infinite content.
It's weird.
Like, and it's so sparse as well.
Like, I haven't seen that at all in my 130-something hours of this game.
And there it is.
You can summon a hut, apparently.
And it will heal you.
Now I know that next time.
Oh, I'm on fire.
That's awesome.
I got to find Wands so I can heal.
What's that?
Is that Ambrosia?
No, I think it's some kind of Akiva Skeevie or something.
No, it's Flammoxium.
Oh, I see a heart!
I can't get in, though.
Rip!
Oh, that sucks.
What a tease.
I need to find something stat.
I could bring this.
Well, that's a hell of a long way to transport something explosive.
That's not gonna happen.
Please don't kill me.
Can I get in there, at least?
Why does everything have to be inside a rock when I can't dig?
Oh, that's a lot of fire.
It's a little bit...
Dammit, I can't get in there, either.
These guys have one weakness.
They can't look up.
It's crazy.
What is this wood, anyway?
Like, this looks so odd to me.
Also, there's a wand over there.
I gotta grab it, if I can.
Tell me it's not embedded in the fucking mountain.
I don't think it is.
I can probably go around.
Man, cold pits with no digging is rough.
Also, because of all the gold you see around, you can't get to.
It's just a huge tease.
Concentrated...
Oh, here we go, here we go.
Here we go.
Oh, that's lovely.
That's healing and it's digging at the same time.
In fact, there's something in there.
Look at how much it heals.
Fantastic.
Go.
No, I thought I saw a connection.
Okay, never mind.
Let me dig over here, because we saw a...
part.
Where was it?
Was it up here to the left?
I think it was over here.
There's a wand here.
Let me dig to that.
Not bad.
Oh, I put this here.
I'm pretty sure the heart I saw was to the left, because this one I saw afterwards.
And I came from over here somewhere.
There it is.
Nice!
Now we heal up.
Fuck yeah.
Wand experimenter?
Amazing.
Wow, that was terrible aim.
Oh, wait.
Nothing in there.
Okay, break work.
That means we're at the bottom.
Oh, I can't even get in here.
Okay, I can.
Uh, what do you do?
I don't care what you do.
You're dead.
I'm actually out of water.
Sir.
Okay.
Nothing there.
What is inside of here?
Moss and fungal soil.
Ah, I'm gonna go back and get high.
We have a whole farm growing right now.
Lots of crops.
Close.
Whoa!
I need a little bit of water here.
Just a bit.
There we go.
That's all I need.
Full water.
Fuck!
I forgot that healed me.
Should have saved it.
Eh.
It was the other one that's empty.
There's something in here.
Or not.
You're in there, but there's nothing else in there.
There's no heart, right, or something?
Okay.
I want to go to fungal caverns, because there's lots of ones there, which means lots of healing, and we can sustain ourselves while exploring.
I think it's the right choice to make.
Except, how do we get there?
We set that on fire.
That's gonna take a while.
This one is empty now.
Let me see if I can't find a way around.
I just feel like I've been up here already.
This is a very weird layout that's been generated here.
Okay, there's a way in, actually.
That makes me happy now.
Whoa!
Yeah, this is how we get in.
Oh, there's gonna be toxic shit everywhere.
Please die, please die, please die.
Where's mom?
Mom?
I think there is no mom.
There's a wand, though.
Ah, shit.
Yikes!
Hopefully, there's something I can dig within that wand.
Maybe...
Oh, wait, I need to not use this yet, because it's actually healing.
What do we have here?
Ho-ho.
Something tells me this is a bad idea to be shooting this.
I mean, I am a wand experimenter, but...
You know.
Maybe that's a bit too much.
I'm taking it, though, because the digging is nice.
Maybe I can try it while falling.
You know, at maximum speed, I plop it down.
Hopefully, I won't die.
I'm so tempted to try it right now.
Come on, show me the hearts.
What is that?
Fermil.
And teleportation.
So, I gotta get in there.
Alright.
Man, where are these caverns at?
Oh, it's right here.
Pfft.
Why does it always happen when I ask?
Oh, these guys are so annoying.
Whoa.
Someone exploded.
Uh, I can't get in there.
Oh, wait, do we have a spawner?
Their nest?
Oh, there is... there is... shit.
How am I gonna even get to that?
Oh, fuck no.
Oh...
Oh my...
Welcome to fungal caverns where you die immediately.
Heal me, heal me, heal me, heal me, heal me.
This fucking place, I swear to god.
Alright, calm down.
There's a wand up there.
I wanna see what it is.
That's sick.
That is really sick.
Thanks.
There's a teleport on that.
Which is awesome balls.
But it also shoots all kinds of other crap.
And that's a bit scary.
So, healing with it, I'm not so sure.
But taking it back with us, fuck yeah.
Whoa, whoa!
Oh no.
Shit, shit, shit.
Okay, we gotta heal with it.
Ah, so what is the worst that can happen?
Honestly, it's not that bad.
We can do this.
Yeah.
There's an egg.
There we go, there's a teleport.
That's blood mist.
There it is.
Healing is okay.
Now, this guy's an issue because we have no damage.
Oh, but circle of stillness.
And tablet.
Oh, but he's in water, so...
That's gonna slow down the tablet.
This is bad.
So what do we do?
You guessed it.
We're getting high.
Do it.
What is the breakpoint?
So we're at 200 seconds now.
Okay, so that's enough.
Oh shit.
Wait, what?
I'm poisoned.
Oh no.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Copper got turned into poison.
That's just unreal.
Oh no.
Whatever.
It is what it is.
This potion is very dangerous.
Oh my goodness.
Ho!
Nice.
Oh my goodness.
Stop!
Okay, so I got a heal.
Nice.
I could heal with this, but I'm scared of it.
Huh?
Oh no.
I'm gonna circle up Stillness as fool.
Oh, he's gone.
Let me be ready.
The fuck off, man.
Are we done?
Oh no.
Come here!
Yes!
Don't destroy that explosive!
Don't destroy...
Nuts.
It's bad.
It's real bad.
This guy down there scares me as well.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
What?
You're frozen!
How come your circuits don't get frozen?
That's a hundred deaths.
That was bullshit.
He was totally frozen.
The effect was on him.
He was blue.
He was frozen.
He didn't move.
Like, what is that?
I feel cheated.
God damn it, man.
Okay.
Bro, I haven't been to a easy base in like 15 runs.
I can't get there anymore.
Like, I've lost the ability to get any further than...
I guess...
Wait, where did I...
I guess frozen wastes?
Whatever the fuck it's called.
Snowy deaths.
I can't get any further than that.
It's fucking over.
What?
Oh, that's berserk.
Oh, no.
Yeah, that's not helping.
Yeah, this is a great start.
And now I'm poisoned.
I don't even care.
This move.
No water here.
There's water up there, of course.
I need to drink this.
Do more damage.
Nice.
Oh.
Blow it up.
Let's get drunk.
Yep.
I saw that one coming a mile away.
Wait, somehow the oil put out the fire?
I was expecting that to do the opposite, but okay.
What a potion!
Thank you!
The game was like, okay, you've suffered enough here.
I have a water potion.
Let me check this wand.
Also, I'm slippery AF.
I gotta get that tablet, though.
It's actually omega important.
Look at this fool up there.
What is he doing here?
I thought he was restrained to...
What's it called?
The other place here.
The unstabilized mines or whatever.
Collapsed mines.
All right.
Ah, can't get through here.
I'm gonna bomb my way through.
Too lazy.
This is the impatient run.
In this run, I'm gonna be as impatient as possible, because something needs to change.
My current playstyle is not getting me anywhere, so we need to change it up.
We need to do opposite of what I did before.
Play risky, play impatient, and play dumb.
Well, one could argue I played dumb before as well, but...
So there's two shotguns down there and a portal.
I'm gonna grab the tablet.
I'm gonna hit them with the tablet, and then I'm gonna go through the portal.
Give me that.
Here we go.
Watch this.
If I miss with this tablet, I'm just gonna jump through.
Bop.
I missed.
Let's do this real quick.
There's no way they're gonna hit us in time.
That was scary.
Wow.
Goddamn.
Holy shit.
Trick grade slime blood?
Wait a minute.
Slime no longer slows you down, and you have higher projectile resistance.
When I'm slimed or just in general, I have higher projectile resistance.
The way it's written makes it sound like I...
Oh yeah, and by the way, you also have higher projectile resistance as an added bonus on top of everything.
But I think it's maybe only when I'm slimed.
I don't know.
Extra perk.
I think that one is a no-brainer.
You gotta take that one.
Okay.
Um...
Can I do any form of digging?
No.
Nope.
I will take this.
And I will take...
Oh, there's only 25 of those.
That sucks.
We need some actual damage here.
I don't know what.
Oh, but hold on.
I need this right now.
We're doing that one.
Ah, the recharge is horrible.
Yeah, do that.
We have some digging at least.
And that is it.
All right.
That's my setup.
69 monies.
Watch this.
You piece of shit!
Can't believe he got a shot in on me there.
Okay, I can get in there.
Oh my god, this one sucks.
It takes forever to re- Oh, wow.
All right, guess I'm not doing that.
I mean, I knew it was shit.
Just not that shit.
Okay, because I'm going down.
I can destroy that.
Now we have mana again.
That was a terrible shot.
All right, let's take another round.
It's going to take a while to get in there, but I bet you it's going to be worth it.
There's going to be two black holes and add mana, triggers, and all kinds of other stuff.
Just watch.
What?
This guy is the master of dodging.
Okay, let's go find that sick wand up here.
It's going to contain all my dreams.
Are you ready?
Watch.
Exactly.
We can dig now.
Hahaha.
Much more consistently.
Oh, yeah, look at that.
Oh, that's so good.
That's so good.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I'm hurting myself with this.
Oh, I killed something.
How come that guy doesn't shoot me?
So I think he can only shoot up 45 degrees of where he's standing.
Seem to be the limit there.
If you're any more than 45, you are golden.
Whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop.
Remember, do not play patient.
Play impatient.
Just go ham.
We don't wait for this to subside, we go.
Shit, I went into my own thingy.
That was bad.
I got it.
Yes.
Nice.
I'm just going to replace this.
No, that one.
Oi, oi, oi, oi, oi.
Okay.
I feel like I'm finding way less hearts than I usually do today.
Like, I think today in total, I found three.
How is it even possible?
I'm so unlucky.
Oh.
Oh my god, my wand sucks so much.
It's wild.
I'm tickling them.
I think I kind of should have taken the slime part, because the slime really is annoying.
Oh, Ambrosia.
That is intriguing.
Don't break the Ambrosia.
Let's wait for that one.
All right, not bad.
Oh, hello.
There's always something in this little space.
Well, almost something.
Almost always.
This time, there was an enemy.
But a lot of times, there's a chest in there.
It's actually kind of recognizable.
The shape looks like Italy.
Now, I did collapse the mountain, so I can't really change my get-up here.
Just annoying.
I'm kind of stuck with what I've got, for the time being.
Unless I just happen to find a better wand outright, which is rare.
Let's go left.
Maybe I can go to fungal caverns and just quickly poke inside and grab if there's any wands right at the edge, because usually those wands are really good.
But I'm not going to go in there proper.
No way.
This guy won't die.
It's insane.
What the fuck is going on?
There we go.
Sure.
Holy crap, that wand sucked dick.
That was unreal.
I'm getting mad.
That's me getting mad right there.
I kicked that shit.
Now, look at this.
Three wands immediately.
No, wait, that's a non-wand.
Let's see what I got.
That one, that's not...
That's a bit of digging.
Poor man's digging.
Already, we have better luck.
Can I get in there?
Yes, I can.
Oh, but it's going to be a little risky.
Yes.
Oh, no.
Hey, I'll take it.
You know what I think it is?
The reason we haven't been able to go anywhere today or succeed is because we never take the health on the mountain.
There's got to be something where if you take that, you get more luck in the game.
Probably not.
But I believe it.
I have become superstitious.
Kind of looks like a bow that we have on right now.
Like a compound bow.
A modern bow.
And a tablet.
And there it is.
Now we can't lose.
Watch.
That's all it takes.
Polymorphine.
I will take it just to experiment with the liquids.
Really?
Oh, that was cool.
Did you see that?
The way when it flew up.
It set everything on fire on the way up.
That was really cool.
Nice effect.
There's almost never anything over here.
Never any enemies.
Never any wands.
Or hearts or anything.
So there's blood and toxic sludge here.
Let's put in some polymorphine.
Do I make something?
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I do.
I think.
I make chaotic.
I thi- Wait, am I?
Huh.
Hold on.
I'm not sure.
Maybe there was a bit of it in there.
I don't think so.
I think that something happened.
Hmm.
I mean, it does make sense.
If you put something toxic or whatever into polymorphine, maybe it corrupts it and it becomes unpredictable.
Let's try here.
So there's oil now.
Polymorphine.
Those two together do nothing.
But if I add acceleration...
Maybe that acts as an, like, as some sort of accelerant, you know?
Like a catalyst.
Water.
Mix it.
Okay, it doesn't do anything.
Wait, am I drunk?
Why am I not hitting anything?
I really dislike these hemispheres today.
I just feel like they're- they have nothing in here.
Like, I don't even know if I found a single heart in one of these hemispheres today.
Maybe one.
But I don't remember it.
Let me get that tablet.
Oh, I already- Oh, wait, wait!
Emerald tablet.
It's the first time I've had it.
We need to fill out the Rosetta Stone now.
I'm gonna take a picture of it.
This is quite big.
Quick, there we go.
And then, there.
All right.
At least I can make some progress here.
I can't seem to make progress in the game itself, so we make progress here.
That's something, at least.
Let's see here.
What are we missing?
J.
Do we have a J?
As all things have been said and rose, mediation of one.
Shit.
It's unreal.
There's no J in here.
Certain most true.
Hold on a second.
Dude.
It says- Wait, where's-
It says that that which is below is like that which is above.
And that which is above is like that which is below.
To do the miracles of one only thing.
And as all things have been and arose from one by the mediation of one.
So all things have their birth from this one thing by adaptation.
So I think it's basically saying these levels that I'm in here.
Are similar to the stuff you find in the sky.
Remember, we saw the art up there, but it like a scuffed version of it.
And then we saw the vault, but a scuffed version of it.
And we also saw a little bit of the jungle, I think.
And then we died.
So it's basically revealing that actually.
At that point.
Anyway.
So we don't have a J.
That's sad.
But do we have something else?
A, A, B, C, D...
Oh, C maybe.
Oh, certain.
Okay, we do.
It's like an S.
Okay, that's nice.
That's something.
We can work with that.
Let me see the S.
Am I looking right?
One, two, three, four, five.
Yep.
It's like a weird triangle with a line at the bottom.
Something less than or equal to.
And let's see.
Kind of looks like an S.
Okay, A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J.
We don't have a J.
K maybe.
Let's see.
I don't think we have a K.
That's insane.
There's so much text here.
Miracles.
Okay, there's no K.
O, P, Q.
There's no Q either.
R, S, T, U, V.
I think we have most.
Honestly, I think if we end up translating something and we get most of a word, we can probably assume what the last part means.
You know, if you have like four out of five letters, I mean, you can figure it out.
At that point.
But first, we got to find some...
First, I got to not die in this game.
So I can get to the places that have interesting lore, hopefully, that we can translate.
And we can solve some of these puzzles that are in this game.
Some of these mysteries that elude me.
That's a dead end.
But it's not.
Anything up here?
Below it.
Blood potion.
Or...
Gently?
Good.
What I really need is vampirism.
It's like my good luck charm.
You know what?
It may actually be my number one now.
The more I think about it, it's just a guaranteed way to get to late game.
Because you can reliably heal anywhere.
It's insane.
And it's just...
It's taking up one perk slot, of course.
But you're going to get so many perks in the late game anyway.
It's not going to matter.
I think it may be my number one perk.
Closely followed by Tinka with Wands everywhere.
Because without it, I'm kind of stuck here.
I just don't have the skills to reliably get to endgame without having it.
There's too much fucking shit happening on the screen.
Too many explosions.
I will die.
Like, you will take damage, right?
Or at least I will.
Okay, so I'm going to use my tablet here.
Bump!
I blocked his attack with the tablet.
It happened again.
Wait, can I just hold it in front of me and I'm not going to take damage?
That's kind of wild.
No, I cannot.
Okay, it was a test.
You are pissing me off, sir.
There we go.
You didn't even die.
Great.
Now I'm dying.
Oh my goodness!
All right, you get to live.
I don't give a shit.
It's not worth it.
Killing you.
What a joke.
All my HP is gone now.
I'm going to get that wand.
I hate the hemisphere so much.
I'm going to leave.
I'm taking a portal.
Don't even care.
Holy crap.
Teleport, nice.
Extra life.
Right now, for me, that is useless because it's pretty much just like, oh, you gain 100 more health.
That's all that means to me right now because if I can't heal, you know...
I mean, obviously, it can save your life down the road, but...
I need vampirism.
Or that.
Thanks.
Now I need vampirism.
And I can't get these, but that's okay.
Let's go.
Also, how does this work?
It's like...
It's definitely better than my main wand.
Yeah.
The coal pits.
I have returned.
You know what?
I have a new...
Let's try something new.
Something drastic and new.
I'm going straight to the fungal grove.
Or the fungal caverns.
The mushroom area.
I'm finding a sick wand and some sick spells in there immediately.
I don't want to waste my time with this pre-area.
We're going straight there.
If we die, that's fine.
Then we go again.
But right now, I have 135 HP.
It's my max HP right now.
May as well use it there.
That's my argument.
You got to try something new.
And you know what?
I have six of these and 12 dynamite.
That can do some damage in there.
What the hell's happening there?
Everything's on fire.
Whoa!
All right, matter eater.
Makes a projectile eat the environment as it flies.
Say what now?
That sounds very intriguing.
I'll try it.
Thank you very much.
No, we're going left.
I kind of want to try this immediately.
Hold on.
Whoa!
Wait, what?
Okay, yeah, that's useless.
It explodes on me for some reason.
I don't understand what's going on there.
I need to put some other projectile on that for sure.
Dynamite immediately just explodes.
I don't know why.
It didn't fly through any environment.
Okay, what I am going to do is use my two and three, two and three, two and three.
There we go.
This guy right here can fuck off.
Oh, God.
Oh, no.
It's going to be impossible to deal with those guys.
I don't have the means.
That's okay.
Show me some ones.
Pheromone.
Okay, get me high.
There's a chance.
That we will transform poison into water or something.
Or into Ambrosia.
Actually, that would be bad because enemies also get it.
What do we get?
Vomit.
Really?
Wait a minute.
No.
Fucking water got transformed into vomit.
Is that real?
Oh, man.
Well, that's great.
That's just fantastic.
That's electrified.
That's flammable gas.
And I can't go anywhere here.
Wait, is that a wand right there?
No, it's meat.
Okay.
I think this run may be ripped already because of that transformation.
Oh, no.
Ah, I guess I can dynamite you.
Okay, that works.
Fuck me.
Now, these guys are going to kill me for sure.
I can't deal with them.
Okay, that was scary.
All of that just to get a wand.
Where is it?
All right.
That is not very enticing.
Slime potion.
Wait, why is vomit orange?
Fuck.
Didn't mean to break that.
Is this guy going to make them blind?
What are you going to do?
I gave them an egg.
Yo, the egg does decent damage when you hit them with it.
What?
This guy just won't die.
Now he will.
Nice.
I feel like I just want to ignore these.
Just ignore the enemies.
What the fuck is that?
Oh, it's vomit.
Oh, I'm frozen forever.
I think I'm dead here.
Bad spot to be in.
This is really bad.
Although they can't really get to me here.
Wait, are they killing each other?
What's happening?
Also, I'm stuck.
I can't move my character.
There we go.
Oh, fuck me, the Huerta.
Yeah, just take me on to the next.
Shit run anyways.
I'm getting really impatient in this game right now, man.
I'm tired of doing the hemisphere.
Bomb?
Yeah.
Just bomb everything.
I need to release my anchor on something in this game.
Oh, that's interesting.
Look at this.
Is that a button?
Pressure plate or something.
No.
That's very interesting.
We got some monies.
It's not a bad start.
Dude, what the hell?
Look at all this.
Feels like there fell...
10 tons of acid here.
Oh, and there's an Ookuskibiya.
Oh, I see what's happened.
This was a trap.
Whoops.
I see what's happening here.
Oh my god.
Okay.
Bad.
That's levitation.
That means we can get...
We can get up to the top of the mountain.
Also, me becoming superstitious didn't work, unfortunately.
Even though I grabbed that health up there, it didn't do anything for me.
I still made stupid decisions.
But now we can get into that cave.
We have a torch.
And this guy has a wand.
Kill himself.
Look at all these hortas.
Yeah.
Amazing.
Oh, fuck.
What is down there?
Okay.
Thought there was a flask.
Did I check this wand?
I think I did.
Those big guys are actually easier to kill than the small ones.
Chaotic polymorphine.
That's not what you want.
Okay, not bad.
400 monies already?
This is actually a pretty decent start.
Probably the best start I've had.
Today, at least.
Collapsed mines.
Rain.
Nah.
I like my bombs.
When they're empty, I'll take it, I think.
Okay.
I'm gonna blow this up as...
No, I can get up here.
Nice.
Oh, I thought he was alive.
He looked so alive there.
And that gives me double gold.
Damn frogs.
Protecting ambrosia.
Don't hit the ambrosia.
Okay.
Let me put this here.
Bring some of that.
And let's go.
I have two bombs left and a torch.
It may be enough.
Let's go in the cave.
And you know what?
I think I've changed my stance on the whole saving up heals.
I think you heal whenever you can.
Because later on, if you can get to the ancient laboratory and kill that guy.
Well, assuming you find healing, of course.
This is all assuming you find healing.
You can have infinite.
Yeah, I guess it depends whether or not you find that.
Which is a bit of a variable.
But nice.
And then we take this because we can see now.
Spillunking.
Aha.
Nice.
Go.
Okay.
Now I'm here.
I can make a hole.
Boink.
Shit, it's too far down.
Now it's actually fine.
But I'm trapped still.
This is bad.
Okay, that's not gonna work.
We need to go here.
Grab some air here and down.
We need more momentum.
There we go.
Okay, there's still healing in there, but I'm not taking it just yet.
I'm taking the healing in the portal now.
Oh, actually.
No, I'm taking this here.
No, I'm not.
Yes, I am.
A lot of things went through my mind right now.
I reasoned all kinds of things.
I have settled on this now.
Okay.
Always casts critical plus.
That's not bad.
But the wand is shuffled so it sucks.
So RIP there.
Oh, this one.
Lower spread extra damage.
Fantastic perk.
What about my wands?
This is an okay wand, but kind of a high recharge time.
That one is decent.
Now what do I want to make?
Yeah, I don't know.
Maybe this is the best for now.
Just because of the critical.
So the eggs.
I don't like eggs.
But the fact there's only two in this thing makes me think it's really good.
Just every time I've tried them, it feels like it's not very good at all.
I got to try more, but I think I'll do it when I have the opportunity to try them where they're infinite.
Okay, so right now, this one always casts critical plus.
And shoots four at the same time.
So I'm just going to put all kinds of shit in here.
I don't really...
Man, there's just no damage spells here.
This is wild.
Holy recharge!
Yeah, never mind.
That sucks.
That's also terrible.
We're going to be working with terrible wands.
Yeah.
I can't do any digging.
Actually, I can.
But if I dig, I have to deal with steward and I can't do that.
Fuck.
Wait a minute.
Put this here.
Let me think.
Luminous drill with timer.
Do we have a nice mana recharge wand?
No, I can't buy anything anymore.
That's not bad.
That's a lot of digging there.
That's too slow.
That's terrible.
This is the one.
Okay, we can use that.
I do have a...
I don't even have a tablet!
Fuck!
I was going to try the kick.
Maybe the...
Okay, you know what?
We're going to try something completely new here.
This is revolutionary, okay?
Put them here.
I'm going to try and summon a million of these and hopefully they will kill them.
Who knows?
Maybe it works.
Yeah, that's the deal.
We're going to try something new.
Maybe that's what steward needs.
A bit of that.
Okay.
Let's go.
Let's start digging.
In fact, maybe we get into a position where...
Hold on, is there anything I can do here?
Let me think.
Oh, wait, I can't buy these anyway.
I should probably take the...
Unless I take the health when I'm low HP.
You know, when I'm fighting a little bit and then I take the HP.
It's a bit risky.
I guess I'll dig up here.
Make him angry.
Yo, steward.
Come here.
There we go.
Bonk.
Oh my god, he just kills them instantly.
Get him.
Come on, guys.
Eel.
I ran out.
There's no more.
Shoot him, guys.
What the fuck are you doing?
Come on.
Fucking useless.
This... this spell sucks so much.
Nah, they don't do anything.
I'm stuck also.
I... yeah.
Whatever.
Whatever, dude.
Oh, look at this.
Looks like a big wave.
I have unstable crystal.
I haven't seen that in...
20 runs.
That is supremely rare.
I am at my wits and regarding steward.
Like, you basically... you essentially have to get lucky.
With the spells you find in the hemisphere.
And what you have in the shop.
Just... just...
Yeah.
RNG.
Also, I gotta...
Okay, so this time I'm gonna try and get that fucking tablet.
Before I go through the portal.
It's gotta be my priority.
Just so I can try that strategy.
We gotta try the tablet kick.
Because if you kick it, it actually gets more momentum.
Oh, I can get that.
Burst of air.
Show me the tablet.
That's dead end.
Okay, here we are.
Oh, that was fast.
There we go.
Beautiful start.
We gotta blow this up.
That almost fell on my head.
Okay, tablet is in hand.
Let me do some quick testing here.
So when I throw...
That's the speed.
But watch this.
If I position myself correctly.
Oh yeah, that's definitely...
And maybe the rotation of this thing actually adds damage.
Who knows?
Maybe the rotation of the object is also impacting the...
What you would call it?
Momentum in the game, you know?
Okay, that thing.
I can get in.
Finally, we get a heart here.
Lovely stuff.
Wait, what?
Never mind, it was a heal.
Oh my goodness.
That's just fantastic.
I have never seen that either in this game, by the way.
That is the first time I've ever seen that.
Getting lots of firsts today.
What
is this?
It's Pete.
Who?
Pete!
You know Pete, from accounting.
Good old Pete.
Pete loves to rock and roll.
And Pete also happens to be the mole.
You can't trust him.
I've seen him.
The stuff he does around the coffee machine?
Bro, you wouldn't believe.
Coffee bags on fire.
Off the shoulder of Orion.
What's up with all this acid?
Can we not?
Maybe?
Boink!
Losing all my HP here.
Come on, remove it!
Just get in.
What do we got?
Shit spells.
Invisibility, though.
The fucking tablet!
It's not on me!
I hate everything.
Right, I don't have money for this.
Or that.
I can buy this!
I'll buy it.
Because it actually has kind of good stats.
Wait, this is even better.
No, it's not.
It's a shitty mana recharge.
Wait, put this here?
All right, we're gonna try a new strategy.
I'm bee lining the portal now.
We gotta try something new here.
Something new needs to happen here.
Okay.
Okay!
Fuck yeah!
There's an add mana here.
But I like this.
Yes, yes.
Wait, what just happened?
Something just exploded.
That's weird.
Okay, so what do we have?
Vampirism!
And now the run is saved.
The run is actually saved now.
Okay, watch this.
I'm actually...
I'm actually gonna ignore every enemy.
I'm trying something completely new here.
We're going straight to the portal.
I don't give a fuck.
Oh, wow.
Maybe I do give a fuck.
A little...
I give a tiny bit of a fuck here!
Go invisible!
Why will my character go invisible for fuck's sake?
I guess I must have been filled with stain.
More like this stain.
Fucking hell, man.
All right, I'm beelining the portals.
We're trying...
I'm going straight to the end now.
Hold on, I'm taking that though.
Thanks.
What is that?
Unstable, you know?
Drink it.
Thanks.
I don't...
I don't care.
Drink it.
Again.
Nice.
That's cool.
Again.
All right.
Trying something new.
Don't be afraid of the teleportation.
I'm grabbing this tablet now.
We're leaving.
Oh, I'm here.
All right.
Again.
There we go.
Cool.
We have no money though.
But that's okay.
Wait, what is that?
Summon platform.
Have I ever seen that?
I feel like that's a new one.
Homing, fast and levitation, kills the mana.
How about...
Homing.
And now we got to be careful with spells because they will actually fuck us.
I'm going straight for the portal.
Oh.
Yeah, especially...
Look, look, look, look.
It's this bad, this bad, this bad, this bad, this bad!
I don't give a fuck.
We're speedrunning.
Speedrun!
Heal up.
No money still.
I don't care.
What's that?
That's new.
Circle of displacement.
Huh?
Well, when I have money, I'll get it.
Pacifist's reward.
Never mind.
I have money, guys.
Gamble?
Oh, we're doing nothing but gambling this run.
Living on the edge.
Extra perk.
Yeah.
Wait, does that mean...
Okay.
Never mind.
So we have homing as well.
Give me that.
Give me that because I need to see what it is.
A field of teleportative magic.
Sure.
Do it.
Hah!
Wait, what?
Holy crap.
All right.
All right, cool.
So wait, hold on.
A pacifist's reward?
Did we actually get that because we didn't kill anyone?
No way.
Oh, I don't want to go through that again.
Or do I?
Dude!
I have figured out a way to get out of the mountain, of course.
Without...
Oh, it's a little bit unpredictable, I guess.
But it works.
Like, I can either use this or this, right?
But since I'm here now, let's do something.
Well, I can't really do much.
I'll do that.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
This is the digger!
We're digging!
That's the best.
Yeah, that's cool.
All right.
Go.
There we go.
Don't kill me.
Don't you kill me.
Toxic sludge potion.
I'm being very radical in my approach to the game right now.
Damn.
1200 mana, though?
Whoa.
Oh, shit.
Don't follow me.
Don't follow me!
Oh, I'm dead.
Oh, somehow I'm not dead.
No one mana.
Fucking eggs.
Sure.
Why not?
Let's egg it up.
Oh, wait, there's a portal right down there.
That thing got hit.
That's unreal.
Okay, we're not killing anyone.
We're trying to do the pacifist thing now.
Oh, man.
I'm farming kills today.
Or, like, deaths, I mean.
The air feels heavy.
I don't give a fuck about the air.
Fucking!
Okay, I didn't kill anyone yet.
They're alive.
I killed nobody.
Everyone is still alive and kicking.
Don't kill me.
Huerta!
Leave me alone!
Ah, dead end!
I don't want to kick.
I want to pet.
I want to pet the hammerses.
I want to pet the Huertas.
I even want to pet the Stendaris.
Run!
Where do I go?
Oh, I really want that.
I can get it.
Hopefully that fire doesn't kill anybody.
Order me.
I'm going in.
Please don't die in the fire now.
Run!
Okay, he died.
Fuck!
Oh, thanks.
He opened the door for me.
I can't believe I haven't lost a single point of health.
Like, what's going on?
How is possible?
Me no no.
Did it work?
I didn't personally kill anyone.
It worked!
Cool.
What's that?
Yes!
Oh, man.
Oh, fuck that shit.
No, we're taking this.
100% though, friendo.
Oh, this is the run.
Now I just need to leave here without...
Shit, I can't.
I can't.
Hmm.
If only I had 30 bucks.
That's all a man needs.
You're not going to give me bucks, are you?
Why you have no bucks?
Come on, man.
Can we dummy this?
0.47, 0.27.
So if I just put one of these in here, that should only use...
Wait, what?
Oh, wait, no, no, no.
Ah, here we go.
Man, look at how this wand looks.
Looks like a star.
It's kind of cool.
I like the design on it.
I mean, that does six damage per shot now, I guess.
No, but we got to go with this.
No, where's the big one?
Oh, that was last run.
Never mind.
Okay, doesn't work like I think it does.
We're going to do that.
Keep it simple.
Let's go.
I'm going pacifist.
I'm not killing nobody.
I wonder if I...
Okay, hold on.
If I tablet enemies, is that considered not killing them?
That's an accident.
I dropped the tablet.
Oops, you know, fumble fingers.
I just don't have a tablet right now.
But I wonder if that counts.
There's a wand up here.
I may go for the wands.
No, only if it's like easily obtainable.
Okay, here we go.
Straight up.
Don't even care.
What I need now is money.
Please.
Please, chest.
Give me the money.
No!
Invisibility will aid me greatly in my quest to be a pacifist.
I still have...
I have two bucks to my name.
We are piss poor, but that's okay.
That's a very decent wand right there.
The dig is real.
It does not dig through this, right?
Oh, hold on.
It does?
Wait.
No, it doesn't rip.
Hey, that's a sick wand.
I shall take it.
And then I shall go invisible at the first opportunity here.
Don't touch the water.
Shit.
Please, stay and go away.
I'm losing my mind.
Here we go.
There we are.
Mother.
What?
How could they see me?
I don't get it.
I don't understand how he saw me.
I was invisible, but okay.
Bullshit.
I can get up here.
I have hit a major roadblock in this game.
I just can't seem to do anything anymore.
Look how foggy it is.
Wait, what's happening?
Why is it so foggy?
Come on.
I'm trying the tablet method here.
I need to test this.
If this actually works, it's kind of crazy.
Okay,
that works.
I need to hit it a little higher here.
There we are.
How is that still?
Come on.
Huh?
They're floating now.
Oh, come on.
Yes!
There it is.
And we have water.
Okay, perfect start.
Now I will only use my tablet because if this all counts as accidents, then I have no blood on my hands.
We're going to see whether or not that works.
Okay, I clearly killed them, but...
maybe not.
Maybe I didn't, you know?
There's a worm.
You.
Shit.
Oh, you bastard.
Oh my god, you bastard!
Took half of my health.
That was a bad throw.
What?
Unreal.
I need my tablet back.
Please, thank you.
There we go.
Boink.
Basically, I need enough money to just buy a couple spells.
There we go.
Thank you.
There's a proof of concept here.
Fuck!
Yeah, we're dead.
We're dead!
Okay, we're going down.
Wait, gotta check this out first though.
Boink.
We missed.
A black hole!
The lock is on our side!
Oh god.
Wait, we have 91.
That's fine.
Let's see.
Does this count?
You have...
It does not count.
Okay, strategy, engage.
Oh, actually, it blocked the shot.
Oh, fuck.
Yeah, it's over.
No, it's not.
Go!
Okay.
No.
Okay, fuck the pacifist.
Shit.
We're back to killing.
You know what?
Fuck you and your architecture.
Wait a minute, I have an idea.
No, no, no.
Don't, don't.
What?
Look at this!
Hahaha, it's down here now.
Uh-oh.
I'm going to the left side.
Where's my tablet?
Where is it?
There it is.
A fuckface.
Oh, dude.
This may be enough momentum.
Hey, that did a lot of damage!
Okay, we're going around.
We're going around.
Also, give me this.
Okay.
Where is he now?
Oh, he's right there.
Okay, then we go left.
We just need enough momentum.
I'm going to try and kick the...
Come on.
Okay, here we go.
Time to hit a field goal.
And while I'm standing here, I think I'm protected against the shots he does.
Because it's gonna bounce off my thing.
I'm gonna try and lure him.
Oh, actually, no, no, no.
I have a better idea.
I'm gonna do it right here.
So, I could throw it down now, but I need to test this.
So, my dude, come here.
Go, hey.
Come on!
Why you like this now?
Come on, man.
All right.
You know what?
Here.
Stay mad.
I'm gonna release you from your torment.
There we go.
All right, Stuart, come here.
Come here.
This is the insane kick.
Fuck!
Fuck you!
Oh, that felt amazing.
All these shit.
Okay.
Trick read.
4x instead of 2x is dropped when death is an accident.
No.
Also, you know what you technically could do?
You could technically take this with you.
Can I...
Okay, I can't kick it, but I can do this.
I could...
If I have, like, infinite black holes, I could take this thing with me all the way down to the bottom if I wanted to.
And I...
I wonder...
Hold on.
Let's say I take this thing all the way down to the next mountain.
I wonder if I then use this, if it will be using it on this, on these perks here, or on the perks in the next mountain.
I wonder if it stays tied, you know what I mean?
I'm actually gonna try that at some point.
Because imagine if you can have a low...
Oh wait, no, but they have the same prices, don't they?
In any case, I want to test it because it seems interesting.
Look at this one.
It always casts reduced recharge time.
Dude, that means this wand is insane.
That is an actual insane wand.
And there's this.
Man, I could have killed him with this actually, but that's fine.
Sure, give me...
Wait, no, no, no.
Hold on, can I even use this properly?
What could I put on it?
180, 51, probably Spirit Bolt is five.
It's only five mana drain.
Yeah, do this, buy it.
There, put these away.
See, that's pretty dope.
Now we just need a bit more.
A bit more.
Let me try this.
Oh wait, is that...
That's the energy orb!
Yes!
Hold on a second.
Wait a minute.
Does the reduced recharge time not cost any mana?
Look at the mana bar.
It's moving very little.
Hold up.
Because that's big, if that's the case.
That's basically a free reduction in castellae and recharge time.
Actually, this wand is also bad.
Never mind, never mind.
Here, there, there, there, there, there.
180, hold on.
Let's say I shoot two.
Oh, I'm too slow.
That was like...
Yeah, it's hard for me to tell.
I don't think it costs mana.
I think that reduced recharge time is free.
And that's kind of dope.
I like this wand.
I like it a lot.
It also does how much damage?
11 plus four explosive.
And we have this wand.
Oh, but I'm poor.
We're poor.
All right, let's go.
Wait, why is everything shaking?
Everything just shook.
Probably just some explosion in the distance.
I'll watch this.
We can get Omega rich really quick.
That's the power of the energy orb.
Oh, but there's a worm on the loose still.
But you know what?
I don't give a fuck.
You know what?
I'm gonna leave him be.
Yeah, let's have some company.
I like that he, you know, he can...
If I'm lucky, he will dig holes for me between the different holy mountains.
And that would be pretty dope.
So yeah, go ahead Matilda.
Have fun.
I just want a bit more mana.
No, money.
Gracias.
Boink.
He also hit me.
That's a weird dig right there.
The worm must have been at work.
Oh, it's not, it's not.
Okay, it's the more powerful version.
Like, like, watch this.
There's something in here.
No, nevermind.
I could have sworn I saw Italy.
Yo!
Look at that!
Matilda.
And that's my path up!
That's what I mean.
Now we have a path up here.
All without using a black hole.
Someone just died.
We're just gonna let Matilda do her work.
I do enjoy these holes.
Ah, come on.
Okay, man.
Matilda has been hard at work the entire level.
It's just holed up.
There's gotta be more than one worm.
And I guess the worm is also killing enemies for me.
Oh, that's this one.
You know, I'm actually gonna take it.
Because it does have one nice spell on it.
Yep, I think I do like that one.
Homebringer, boo.
At least right now I don't really know how to utilize it properly.
Notice how this also has minus 22 spread on.
That wand is sick.
Wait, how is that?
Like, this energy orb actually appears a little further ahead in my wand.
Oh no, it appears at the...
Oh, I see now.
I can actually shoot through walls then.
If they're thin enough.
Depends on the length of my wand.
Ha-ha!
Good shot, bro.
It's a hoodlum.
He teleported himself somewhere.
Berserkium, I will take it.
I wonder if Berserkium works when I throw my tablet.
Okay, here we go.
It's time to hit a field goal.
Gotta place it.
Quick, quick, quick, quick.
Here we go, here we go.
Let's do it, come here!
Come here!
Come on!
Hold on, let me quickly check these while I wait.
Okay, okay, okay.
Oh, he's not coming, he's not coming yet.
That was a black hole.
Worst case, I have a black hole I can escape with.
Come on, man.
Maybe I need to lure him in.
Oh, here he comes, here he comes.
Bro.
Oh, perk lottery.
Come on.
Shit!
Wait.
All right, that's fine with me.
We chilling, go!
Yeah, the gods are angry, I don't give a fuck.
Stay mad.
Stay mad!
Yeah, kill him for me, thank you!
Stuart, you're actually being helpful.
Fucking get out of here.
Ah!
What if I re-roll after I take the thing?
Okay, only two remain right.
Uh...
Sure, why not?
Let me try something new.
All right, Stuart, come here.
In fact, hold on, I have a better idea.
Fuck, get out of here.
I'm just gonna use this.
Whoops.
Hey, Stuart!
Oh, it's very heavy though.
Nah, hold on.
I need something more lightweight.
Gimme that.
So I already hit him for quite a lot.
He should die from a simple throw now.
Watch.
Oh, I need to be... I need to really nail this one.
Come on!
Come on, dude.
You piece of shit.
Alright, I'm coming from the left.
No, wait, there's...
Okay, here we go.
This is my shot.
Go!
Yes, sir!
What a throw!
Uh...
Cool.
Dig.
Dig, dig, dig, dig.
There we go.
Unfortunately, I didn't pick up the money.
Most of it, at least.
Whoosh!
Alright, that's two down.
By the way, didn't I never grab a perk upstairs?
I almost can't believe that.
I have black holes.
Now I take the Matilda Highway.
Bake it.
Wait, what?
Oh, okay.
Let me go check the perks up here.
I don't think I ever took one, because I have two.
Look.
And I got the other one via the perk lottery.
I'm actually blending all these runs together in my head, because I've died so much today.
Like, for a second there, I was like, oh yeah, I have teleport, but I don't.
You know?
Uh... extra health.
Oh wait, I wanted to re-roll this.
Why is that 200?
Shouldn't that be 400?
Wait, how many times did I re-roll?
I re-rolled more than once.
No, I re-rolled once.
Is that even gonna work?
Hold on, we gotta collect some money.
I need to see whether or not that is still tied to that one, or is it tied to another mountain?
Something's going on here that I don't understand.
Hold on.
Hey, give me money.
Oh wait, I don't need to kill enemies.
I can just take gold.
There's literally gold on the floor.
It's like me walking on the sidewalk.
Trying to beg for money when there's money lying on the ground.
Like, why would you beg for the money?
Yeah.
Alright, that's fine.
Dude, what the fuck?
Why is that 200?
I don't understand what's happening.
I'm so curious.
Wait, now it's 800.
Huh.
Did it change it?
It did!
I think I'll take this.
Yeah, fuck toxic shit.
I hate toxic so much.
I gotta get to the bottom of what just happened there, because that is omega confusing.
Okay, so we have teleport.
I'm gonna get some money and come back and get teleport.
That's the next big step.
Look how easy it is to get money when you can dig.
Especially, uh, coal pits.
Has tons of money.
There's gold in them heels!
And that's enough.
Leave that here.
That is already a decent teleporter.
Perfect.
Very nice!
Okay, we're slowly getting set up here.
And I'm enjoying that.
Let's get some more money and then move on.
Damn!
That's a lot of those.
Also, I'm an idiot.
I should put my black holes on one wand.
I don't know why I didn't do that.
Do that.
No, do this!
It's shuffle, but...
That's okay.
Maybe do this instead.
Yeah, that's fine.
Huh?
Also, I need to be eating, uh...
We're drinking the berserkium more.
It really is just extra damage that I don't utilize.
It's dumb not to utilize it.
Okay, I tire off the coal pits.
I will move on.
I could take that.
Not gonna though.
Oh, there's a wand right there.
Hmm, get it.
That guy's gonna be hell to deal with.
Oh wow, oh wow, oh wow.
That's a lot of damage.
Oh, fuck!
Ah, that's... weird.
What if I shoot?
Oh, okay.
Finally.
Look how it spawned water above me.
Hey!
That's not bad.
Hold on.
I have a...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Shit!
I didn't mean to do that.
This needs to be here, so don't confuse myself.
And this needs to be here.
Now, I had a wand in here.
That was quite insane, honestly.
Which one was it?
Maybe it was the one I dropped down here just now.
Something that would be perfect for digging.
Is that it?
No, that's not it.
Maybe that was another run.
Yeah, everything is blending together in my mind.
That's much better already.
Oh, yeah.
Put it on the dummy.
Wait, why am I...
Hold on.
Why is this not shooting really fast?
Oh, because these add castelae!
Holy shit!
That's 0.4 castelae there.
So, it's actually better if I do this.
Whoa, wait a second.
So, that's 0.37, 0.3.
But then, then this always casts.
It's working.
Basically, I don't understand how this is not immediately a machine gun.
That's super confusing to me.
Also, I'm using less mana the more I have these.
The more I have these on here, the less mana I use.
You see that?
Look at my bar.
But if I only use one of them...
Oh, maybe it's the same.
Probably the same.
But one thing I don't think you can go wrong with is this.
Just have one of these on there.
And remove the rest.
Do some more damage with it.
And if I use this instead...
Why is that not super quick?
Okay, that's more like it.
But I think we liked this one.
Whoops, shit.
That one is pretty good.
I'm gonna shuffle, but on average, it's gonna dig pretty well.
And we have that one there.
And teleport is here.
Yep, that's nice.
And then here, we're gonna do that.
Nice!
Very cool.
I'm actually gonna refresh my black holes.
I need to start using these refreshers more.
Okay, let me move on.
Next area.
Get out of there.
Uh-oh.
Man, teleport can get you out of sticky situations in a jiff with
a timer.
That's not a bad wand.
But it is.
Oh my god, can you please fuck off?
Okay, immediately.
Tablet.
What?!
Seda!
Shit!
Wait, we have teleport, teleport, teleport.
Shit, come on!
Uh, forward, forward, forward, forward!
Go!
Oh no, I'm here!
Oh no, oh no!
Oh, I'm so dead, I'm so dead, I'm so dead.
Shit!
Go!
What do we got, what do we got?
Critical hit plus, close call, whatever.
Gimme that.
Ah, this is so over.
Ah, just kill me, dude.
Fuck off, fuck off, man.
I hate this dude, guys, so fucking much.
It's insane!
He's literally the gatekeeper of fun.
Ugh.
Thanks.
Brian.
This guy jumps from the sky and shoots me in the head, it's just a fantastic start here.
Gimme the tablet.
We're back to the drawing board regarding Stuart.
Back to the fucking drawing board.
Maybe the- this is gonna sound so dumb.
Maybe the answer is two tablets.
You kick a field gold one, and then as soon as you kick it, you kick the next.
That's like guaranteed double damage.
Straight up.
It sounds dumb as hell, but I think it'll work.
Uh, oh, nice.
Line me up.
Nice amount of money there.
Ooh, a big one.
Very cool.
Blow it.
Just had to roll to the right.
Ruined my whole plan.
I have no patience for this place, I'm going straight.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
You know what?
These ones.
This is the Stuart killer.
But the issue is, I need to find something that...
is consistent without me having to rely on the goddamn spells.
I'm taking that.
Let's see here.
Can I even do any- oh wait, these actually do digging, right?
I think they do.
Hold up.
This is totally doing something.
Someone's a large serrated disc with a curious flight pattern.
Oh, this is the suicide thing, isn't it?
I mean, if that's what it takes.
Boink!
Yeah, that is, that is curious.
Now, I may have tried this before against Stuart and it just bounced off of his shield.
But we'll have to try it again.
I do have a tablet.
Let me get it ready.
Fuck.
Get out of the way.
Maybe not here.
Maybe I need to put it...
What if I put it right at the edge here so that when he...
I can sort of shoot it a little down.
You know what I mean?
Hmm.
Do I even have- does this even destroy the environment?
Because if not, then it doesn't matter.
Yeah, it doesn't.
Okay, well, in that case, I can't even anger him right now.
And that's that.
Let's go.
Wait, something's happening here.
It's very humid.
Yeah, look at the projectiles.
Everything is super heavy.
Or viscous.
The air is viscous.
Is there a piece of gold in there?
I think there is.
Give me that gold.
Good enough for me.
I have to remember, it also applies to my projectiles.
Oh, that's a dead ass end.
Does this...
Wait, does it always just come back to me?
Okay, so it's actually predictable in that way.
Hmm, not quite.
It- does it come back to where you shot it?
No, it's definitely randomized.
Oh, these are infinite, right?
Yeah.
It's a scary ass pattern they make, but the damage they do is undeniable.
Yeah, that's very scary.
Oh, but if they hit something, it disappears.
So as long as I have good aim, we're fine.
Oh, look how that gets them stuck in them, embedded.
Oh, he died from toxic, I think.
I'm immune to fire.
I think I like the gig of this projectile.
It pleases me greatly.
Okay, those guys got hit by it, but they still moved around.
So the projectile was not stopped in its tracks at that time.
Fuck it, I'm going.
I have no more patience.
Give me the Winnapurks teleport.
Nice, okay, that's not bad.
Oh, is that... Oh, it's not.
Explosion immunity.
That's a must.
You got to do that.
You absolutely got to do that.
Now, what do I do?
I can't even buy that one.
I can only buy this one.
That is not a bad wand.
In fact, that's pretty sick.
I like that.
Damn.
Scary.
I guess I'll come back for you.
This seems pretty sick.
Always casts crit on water enemies.
Or wet enemies.
If I can put like a water modifier on one of my spells, I think I could make something great with that.
Also, do we really need four of these?
Of course we do.
What a question.
Yeah, this one is kind of bad.
Ah, let me put on four.
Let's go.
I have no fear.
The man who fears the saw blade is the man who will meet his demise.
No pain, no gain.
You got to trust in your instinct to dodge.
If you can dodge a saw blade, you can dodge anything.
What do we got?
Green glimmer.
And a magic arrow.
Ah, yeah, sure.
Oh, yeah?
What do you say to that?
I can saw blade in the face.
Shit.
I want to
get in there.
But I can't.
I don't have the means.
Ow!
Wow.
Bro, something tells me my saw blade is not going to do shit against that guy.
Oh, my goodness.
All right, we're leaving.
Already terrible.
Also, I left some health up here, didn't I?
Let me just take that now.
I'm pretty sure I didn't go down here with full health.
I was saving it.
Don't go that way.
Go back where we came from.
Oh, wait, can I not?
I mean, I can.
Fuck.
I don't want to do that.
Nope.
We're leaving.
I'm probably going to die to one of my own saw blades before I reach the portal.
That's my prediction.
Holy shit.
Don't shoot me.
Don't do it.
All right.
Nice.
Sweet cakes.
Well, I have no money for any of this.
But I have money for the perk lottery.
Not that you need money for that.
There's no way I'm surviving all the way to the portal.
I can tell you that.
Point.
This is very effective.
It's going very well.
Oh, no.
We've got mechanical.
Friendo.
How am I going to get through here?
I'm going to blow that up.
That's how.
Shit.
I figured that would happen.
108 deaths.
That's it, man.
No more.
I am losing my patience.
Like, it takes forever to get a good run going.
It's absolutely wild.
I got to Easy Base at least.
That's the most progress I've made in many, many hours of this game.
Congrats on 100 deaths.
Thanks.
That's a big milestone for sure.
Yeah, my patience keep dying on me, Jen.
I don't know why they do so.
I mean, I just threw a couple saw blades here and there, you know, to amputate.
But it doesn't work out.
Man, today was painful.
I'm not going to lie.
What did I even learn today?
I'm not sure.
Not much.
There's this weird thing about this game where you do get better at it the more you play.
But you also get more...
No, you get less patient with it.
At least I do the more you play.
So, you know, your skill goes up.
Oh, let's say it like this.
Okay, we're going to pull up this here.
I'm going to make a new here and here.
So if this...
Oh, hold on.
If this is skill or like skills at the game...
Skill at Noiter.
No, no, no, even better.
I'm going to call it success in Noiter.
Okay, time.
So what happens is you get better at the game because you learn the mechanics, right?
Goes up like that.
You play the game.
You learn the mechanics.
You gain the knowledge.
You know what the spells do.
You know what combinations are good, right?
But then, because of your patience, gets lower because you expect to get further every time you play.
You know, your skill also sort of declines over time.
So in essence, these two add together these two curves and it's more like a thing that goes like that.
In a weird way.
And I think the patience, the loss of patience over time overtakes the knowledge you gain, at least for me.
So I end up being less successful in Noiter as time goes on.
You know what I mean?
So those two graphs somehow add together and that's the result of that.
So in order to succeed, you need to be patient.
Even after 100 runs.
With the knowledge that you've gained.
But it's very, very hard to stay patient.
You know what I mean by that?
You have the exact same thing.
So you know what I mean.
I think you could find a middle ground of patience between how you used to play and how you played today.
Yeah, but here's actually something.
By playing a little impatient today, I did actually learn something.
You can get a pacifist chest.
I didn't know that.
If you don't kill anything, you will get a reward, which is kind of funny.
Maybe too much Noiter for the last week?
Maybe?
I was just so excited to start translating things, man.
And to start getting somewhere with the puzzles and all the mysteries.
And that's why I got so frustrated by dying all the time.
Because I just get reset back to the fucking beginning every time some bullshit happens.
Or the RNG doesn't go my way.
Or Stewart decides to show up, you know?
In the same manner, it's like very much like Rainworld, where you gotta get through so much to get that reward, you know?
So you just gotta push through.
Acceleration for the win indeed.
Also, let me pull the chat over here.
It's off to the side.
You're streamed a lot this week.
I have.
But I've also wanted to play Noiter a lot.
It's like...
I wanna get to the bottom of these things, man.
I wanna explore the rest of the map.
The thing about Noiter, for me right now, is that there's these filters, you know?
So you start somewhere, right?
This is you.
You start over here.
And you move through time.
And in the game, there are certain barriers, okay?
That you have to sort of get through.
And a lot of these are like filters.
It's like, oh, a worm spawns and the gods are angry?
Good luck!
Now you gotta fight Stewart, right?
That's one filter.
Oh, shit, I died.
Okay, so you survived that, right?
Okay, then we need good RNG to get some good spells.
Oh, you didn't find a good one that works with those spells?
Ah, too bad.
You got filtered, you know?
And you got to get through all of these filters to get to a chance, a high probability, of actually completing or getting to the late game where you can do a lot of damage and you can comfortably kill things.
Oh, but you do all of that and you manage to spend 16 hours?
Oh, you get polymorphed and you die instantly, you know?
That's like the ultimate filter in this game.
If these were normal sized filters, that filter is like this sized and it's ever looming and ever present because it's all the time.
Doesn't matter how far you get.
I mean, for me, I'm talking from my perspective, of course, because I don't know.
Maybe there's a way to not get polymorphed.
Like, guaranteed.
I don't know.
Maybe there is.
I just haven't discovered that yet.
Basically, what I'm saying is the game is hard.
It's a hard game.
And similar to Rainworld, you have to keep your head cool.
And stay patient throughout all of these.
You can't falter at any moment because then this right here, this one will get you.
You know?
Oh, you managed to stay cool all the way to here, to the end?
You still got to stay cool because this one will kill you.
The poly filter is brutal indeed.
No one guessed my favorite color?
What the hell, man?
After I took Wertha, Wertha, Wertha?
I don't think I've tried the faster movement perk, but I assume it's just like consuming acceleration.
But don't tell me if it is different.
Maybe it's not.
I'm assuming it's not, now that you ask like that.
Yeah, they're similar in the way that you need to work hard to earn the lure.
Definitely.
Great filter, Kurzgesagt.
Yeah, I was actually thinking about that when I said it.
So yeah, I just got to keep my head cool and not fuck up.
Get some good luck going.
I mean, if you're good enough at the game, which I'm not, I'm assuming you can always get a good run.
But I'm just not skilled enough.
Rainworld rewards you with the lure, whereas Noiter feels more like it's mocking you for trying.
That's actually funny.
I can respect that in some way.
Noiter welcomes you break the game.
Reminds me of Rainworld.
No, not Rainworld.
Risk of rain.
Risk of rain also is completely unfair.
Like the more the time goes on, the more the game becomes bullshit.
So it actually becomes a question of how fast you can become overpowered.
No, you break the game before the game breaks you, sort of.
And it's kind of like that here, except you have more time.
You can take it slow, you know, and yeah.
Exactly, it's a risk, it's a raise against time.
Yeah, definitely.
Risk of rain is fun.
It's actually a lot of fun.
So I actually played risk of rain with a friend.
That was really fun.
I think it was definitely more fun together with someone.
But I never tried to play it alone.
I may start another game next time, actually.
And then do maybe one or two streams of Noiter every week.
Just to be more fresh with the game.
Because I think it's true that if I stream Noiter too much, then I will start to become impatient.
And I will actually play worse because of it.
So if I take other streams and play something else, and then come back with a fresh mind, where it's been a while, I think I'll do much better.
I'm gonna be playing way better, I think.
Try daily run next time?
Oh, for sure.
We're gonna try that.
I also want to try the Twitch integration with Noiter.
Even though it may spoil some things.
I mean, I feel like I'm so far in the game at this point.
Maybe it's okay.
Any particular games in mind?
Actually, not really.
I need to think about it.
I mean, I just need to look at my backlog and decide what sounds cool right now.
You know, what would I like to play?
Maybe I would like a game that isn't too difficult.
Because I feel like I've been playing a lot of those.
I'm getting stretched thin here.
Elden Ring?
On stream?
I think people preferred that on local, but or like recording.
But that could be cool as well on stream.
Honestly, Elden Ring would be a walk in the park for me compared to this.
I'm really good at Souls games.
Like I would murder that shit compared to here.
Yeah, maybe I'll die a couple of times to a boss, but I'll kill it at some point, you know.
Twitch integration and Nightmare are like a thousand times harder than normal.
I mean, I understand Nightmare is, but Twitch integration makes the game harder.
I thought it was more like a fun thing where people could decide certain aspects of the run.
Or maybe that depends on how much of an asshole people are.
If they want to make me suffer or not.
It makes the game harder.
Oh, shit.
Okay, damn.
It's just you throwing obstacles at me.
Oh, I see.
Jen, do you mean like Elden Ring is your top two game?
Oliver is a Soulsborne pro.
Damn right, Hive.
If you've seen my...
What's it called?
Bloodborne.
I nailed that game, man.
That game was a walk in the park.
And I played that game around the same time I played Rainworld.
And whenever I would boot up Bloodborne, I would just be like, ah, okay.
Let's just relax and have a walk in the park.
You know, the contrast between that game and Rainworld was striking.
Like playing Bloodborne at that time was like playing The Sims for me.
Yeah, that game is incredible.
I loved trying to understand the lore in Bloodborne.
I had so much fun with that game.
I took so many notes.
It was crazy.
Oh, you're playing the DLC now, Jen.
That's awesome.
Wow, Elden Ring and Baldur's Gate 3 are tied for first place.
Those are very recent games.
That's amazing.
Amazing games are still being made.
Did you end up understanding it, the Bloodborne lore?
I think so.
About chill games.
Have you played Stardew?
I have played it.
Not very much though.
Maybe like three, four hours of it.
I played it with my friend Kate.
She's played it a lot.
It was a lot of fun.
Very relaxing game.
I loved fishing in that game.
Man, I wish Bloodborne was remastered before I played it.
Now I hear rumors that it's actually gonna be remastered.
So it's like, come on, man.
I've been waiting so many years.
What do you think would be nice games for stream?
I'm looking at my backlog right now, trying to decide.
But I'm probably gonna pick a couple and then put it up for a vote, you know?
If I'm conflicted between a couple choices, I'm just gonna let the community decide on it.
But it's gonna be games that I personally want to play, of course.
Yeah, something chill for sure.
There's been rumors forever.
I can't take it anymore.
I totally understand.
I've been wanting to play Bloodborne for so many years and I've been waiting so patiently for the remake or whatever.
And it never came.
But I finally said, fuck it.
I'm getting it and playing it.
It was amazing, though.
Even on the PS4.
No, wait, I played it on the PS5, but it's actually the PS4 version.
Can you post a link?
Yeah, definitely.
Detroit become human?
That's science fiction, right?
That could be nice.
Or maybe like a puzzle game of some sort would also be nice.
What about Grim Fandango?
I've heard so many things about that game.
It's an old game, but apparently it's good.
I'm just looking at my list here.
I've played The Witness already, you jury.
Or most of it.
I'm like 80% through it, I think.
I got stuck on one puzzle for so long and then I had other stuff in my life and I never got any further.
But that one was nice.
I had a great time with The Witness.
Solid suggestion.
None of the games I like are chill?
I mean, yeah.
Detroit is a good stream game.
Oh, really?
Why is that?
It's a story game, right?
Oh, you know what?
Maybe I should go for...
Oh, no, I was about to say, let's go hardcore Minecraft.
But that's probably gonna be tough as balls.
Super liminal, huh?
Let's see it.
I think it's on my list.
First-person puzzle game.
Okay.
Yeah, that could be cool.
Darkest dungeon.
I've heard good things about it, but I also heard it's difficult.
What about a scary game, guys?
Like, scary games are not difficult.
They're just scary, right?
What about...
What's it called?
This...
Oh, what's it called?
The des- no, not the Descent.
Amnesia.
I played the first Amnesia, and it's- I'm proud of that.
But there's other Amnesias.
Anyone came out, the bunker, and apparently they're not really connected, so I could play them in any order I want.
What about Amnesia, the bunker?
Could that be fun?
Oh, pray.
Yeah.
Have you played Fes?
I have not played Fes.
Or, I don't know how to pronounce it.
Fes?
Fes.
But I think I've heard some of the soundtrack of Fes before.
I don't know how.
I think I found a list once, and I heard some of the music from it, and it was really good.
You would enjoy watching you sob?
I promise I'm not evil.
I feel like Amnesia could be cool.
Or even Alien Isolation, yeah.
Something horror.
Or what about some old games, too?
I have so many old games on my list as well.
Metal Gear.
Always wanted to try that series.
There's a lot of Metal Gear games as well.
Alien Isolation.
There's also Pacific Drive.
I've heard good things about that.
It's quite a recent game.
I don't know.
I'll think about it.
I'm probably gonna put them up for a vote.
Twin Stick Sci-Fi Roguelite Novadrift.
Man, what a sentence.
Wait, what?
Is the game called Novadrift?
Novadrift.
All right, I added that to my backlog.
There's some good games in the last page.
Let me see the last page of my backlog.
Oh, yeah.
Guys, what about Control?
Or like the... I know that Alan Wake is somehow connected to that.
Like, it's a series.
Is that correctly understood?
Like, I should play Alan Wake first.
Oh, there's also Little Nightmares.
What about that?
Is that a horror game?
I don't know what FNAF is.
Hi.
I'm guessing it's an acronym.
Book of Hours.
It's very lore-heavy.
What is that?
That looks interesting.
I'm adding it to the list.
This list is getting dangerously long, guys.
It's like so many games on that list.
I heard Cocoon is good.
It's apparently made by one of the people who did Inside.
And I adore Inside.
Oh, Little Nightmares is very Inside-esque.
Ooh, I like that a lot.
I like that a lot.
Oh, it's a horror game, Hive.
It's an old one.
Extend my lifespan.
We need to extend everyone's lifespan so we can all play old games.
There's too many games and too little time.
Okay, I have some... I have some good...
You guys gave me some good suggestions here.
I will also take another look at the list.
And make a poll about it.
And I think I will actually do the...
the, like, alternate streams between some Noita.
Because I really want to keep playing it.
But I just... I want to succeed in it too.
So I need to take some breaks.
And then play some other games in between.
So yeah.
You love the music?
It's from the Talos Principle.
It's so good.
This is from...
Oh, I'm not gonna reveal.
Actually, I'm not gonna say anymore.
It's from the Talos Principle.
One of the best puzzle games I've played.
Okay, guys.
I will go to bed now because it's quite late.
Thanks for watching.
I will make an update on the YouTube where you can vote for a game at some point.
Maybe tomorrow or the day after.
And we'll find something cool.
I'm just gonna narrow my list down a bit before I do.
I'll see you guys next time.
Have a good day.
Have a good night.
And I'll see you around.
Bye-bye.